<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../../data/Schemas/schema_update_3.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<story>
    <meta>
        <title>The Old House in Vauxhall Walk</title>
        <author>Charlotte Riddell</author>
    </meta>
    <body>
        <chapter>
            <chapTitle>Chapter One</chapTitle>
            <p>
                <speech ref="amb">Houseless—homeless—<scary_word pos="adj" scale="0"
                        >hopeless</scary_word>!</speech>
            </p>
            <plot point="protag"/>
            <p>Many a one who had before him trodden that same street must have uttered the same
                words—the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">weary</scary_word>, the <scary_word
                    pos="adj" scale="0">desolate</scary_word>, the hungry, the forsaken, the waifs
                and strays of struggling humanity that are always coming and going, <scary_word
                    pos="adj" scale="0">cold</scary_word>, starving and miserable, over the
                pavements of Lambeth Parish; but it is open to question whether they were ever
                previously spoken with a more thorough conviction of their truth, or with a feeling
                of keener self-pity, than by the young man who hurried along Vauxhall Walk one rainy
                winter's <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">night</scary_word>, with no overcoat on
                his shoulders and no hat on his head.</p>
            <plot point="intro"/>
            <p>A <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">strange</scary_word> sentence for one-and-twenty to
                give expression to—and it was stranger <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0"
                    >still</scary_word> to come from the lips of a person who looked like and who
                was a gentleman. He did not appear either to have sunk <scary_word pos="mod"
                    scale="i">very</scary_word> far <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0"
                    >down</scary_word> in the good graces of Fortune. There was no sign or token
                which would have induced a passer-by to imagine he had been worsted after a long
                fight with calamity. His boots were not <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0"
                    >worn</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0">down</scary_word> at the heels or <scary_word
                    pos="adj" scale="0">broken</scary_word> at the toes, as many, many boots were
                which dragged and shuffled and scraped along the pavement. His clothes were good and
                fashionably cut, and innocent of the rents and patches and tatters that <scary_word
                    pos="verb" scale="1">slunk</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="adv" scale="1">wretchedly</scary_word> by, crouched in doorways,
                and held out a hand mutely appealing for charity. His face was not pinched with
                famine or lined with <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">wicked</scary_word> wrinkles,
                or brutalised by drink and debauchery, and yet he said and thought he was
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">hopeless</scary_word>, and almost in his young
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">despair</scary_word> spoke the words aloud.</p>
            <p>It was a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">bad</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">night</scary_word> to be about with such a feeling
                in one's heart. The rain was <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">cold</scary_word>,
                pitiless and increasing. A damp, keen wind blew <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0"
                    >down</scary_word> the cross streets leading from the river. The fumes of the
                gas works seemed to <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0">fall</scary_word> with the
                rain. The roadway was muddy; the pavement greasy; the lamps burned <scary_word
                    pos="adv" scale="1">dimly</scary_word>; and that <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                    >dreary</scary_word> district of London looked its <scary_word pos="mod"
                    scale="i">very</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">gloomiest</scary_word> and <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="1">worst</scary_word>.</p>
            <p>Certainly not an <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">evening</scary_word> to be abroad
                without a home to go to, or a sixpence in one's pocket, yet this was the position of
                the young gentleman who, without a hat, strode along Vauxhall Walk, the rain beating
                on his unprotected head.</p>
            <p>Upon the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">houses</scary_word>, so large and good—once
                inhabited by well-to-do citizens, now let out for the most part in floors to weekly
                tenants—he looked enviously. He would have given much to have had a room, or even
                part of one. He had been walking for a long time, ever since <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="0">dark</scary_word> in fact, and <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >dark</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0">falls</scary_word> soon in December. He was tired
                and <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">cold</scary_word> and hungry, and he saw no
                prospect save of pacing the streets all <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >night</scary_word>.</p>
            <p>As he passed one of the lamps, the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >light</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0">falling</scary_word> on his face revealed hadsome
                young features, a mobile, sensitive mouth, and that particular formation of the
                eyebrows—not a frown exactly, but a certain draw of the brows—often considered to
                bespeak genius, but which more surely accompanies an impulsive organisation easily
                pleased, easily depressed, capable of suffering <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i"
                    >very</scary_word> keenly or of enjoying fully. In his short life he had not
                enjoyed much, and he had suffered a good deal. That <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >night</scary_word>, when he walked bareheaded through the rain, affairs had
                come to a crisis. So far as he in his <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >despair</scary_word> felt able to see or reason, the best thing he could do was
                to <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2">die</scary_word>. The world did not want him; he
                would be better out of it.</p>
            <p>The door of one of the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">houses</scary_word> stood
                open, and he could see in the <scary_word pos="adv" scale="1">dimly</scary_word>
                lighted hall some few articles of furniture waiting to be removed. A van stood
                beside the curb, and two men were lifting a table into it as he, for a second,
                paused.</p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">Ah,</speech> he thought, <speech ref="grahamCoulton">even
                    those <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">poor</scary_word> people have some place
                    to go to, some shelter provided, while I have not a roof to cover my head, or a
                    shilling to get a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">night</scary_word>'s
                    lodging.</speech> And he went on fast,, as if memory were spurring him, so fast
                that a man running after had some <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >trouble</scary_word> to overtake him.</p>
            <p><speech ref="william"><character ref="grahamCoulton">Master Graham</character>!
                        <character ref="grahamCoulton">Master Graham</character>!</speech> this man
                exclaimed, breathlessly; and, thus addressed, the young fellow stopped as if he had
                been shot.</p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">Who are you that know me?</speech> he asked, facing
                round.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="william">I'm <character ref="william">William</character>; don't you
                    remember <character ref="william">William</character>, <character
                        ref="grahamCoulton">Master Graham</character>? And, Lord's sake, sir, what
                    are you doing out a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">night</scary_word> like
                    this without your hat?</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">I forgot it,</speech> was the answer; <speech
                    ref="grahamCoulton">and I did not care to go back and fetch it.</speech></p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="william">Then why don't you buy another, sir? You'll catch your death
                    of <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">cold</scary_word>; and besides, you'll excuse
                    me, sir, but it does look odd.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">I know that,</speech> said Master Graham grimly; <speech
                    ref="grahamCoulton">but I haven't a halfpenny in the world.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="william">Have you and the master, then—</speech> began the man, but
                there he hesitated and stopped.</p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">Had a quarrel? Yes, and one that will last us our
                    lives,</speech> finished the other, with a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0"
                    >bitter</scary_word> laugh. <speech ref="grahamCoulton">And where are you going
                    now?</speech></p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="william">Going! Nowhere, except to seek out the softest paving stone,
                    or the shelter of an arch.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="grahamCoulton">You are joking, sir.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="william">I don't feel much in a mood for jesting either.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="william">Will you come back with me, <character ref="grahamCoulton"
                        >Master Graham</character>? We are just at the last of our moving, but there
                    is a spark of <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">fire</scary_word>
                    <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0">still</scary_word> in the grate, and it would be
                    better talking out of this rain. Will you come, sir?</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">Come! Of course I will come,</speech> said the young
                fellow, and, turning, they retraced their steps to the house he had looked into as
                he passed along.</p>
            <p>An <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">old</scary_word>, <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                    >old</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word>, with long, wide hall, stairs
                low, easy of ascent, with <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">deep</scary_word> cornices
                to the ceilings, and oak floorings, and mahogany doors, which <scary_word pos="adv"
                    scale="0">still</scary_word> spoke mutely of the wealth and stability of the
                original owner, who lived before the Tradescants and Ashmoles were thought of, and
                had been sleeping far longer than they, in St Mary's churchyard, hard by the
                archbishop's palace.</p>
            <p><speech ref="william">Step upstairs, sir,</speech>
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0">entreated</scary_word> the departing tenant;
                    <speech ref="william">it's <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">cold</scary_word>
                    <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0">down</scary_word> here, with the door standing
                    wide.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">Had you the whole <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                        >house</scary_word>, then, <character ref="william"
                    >William</character>?</speech> asked <character ref="grahamCoulton">Graham
                    Coulton</character>, in some surprise.</p>
            <p><speech ref="william">The whole of it, and right sorry I, for one, am to leave it;
                    but nothing else would serve my wife. This room, sir,</speech> and with a little
                conscious pride, <character ref="william">William</character>, doing the honours of
                his late residence, asked his guest into a spacious apartment occupying the full
                width of the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">house</scary_word> on the first
                floor.</p>
            <p>Tired though he was, the young man could not repress an exclamation of
                astonishment.</p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">Why, we have nothing so large as this at home, <character
                        ref="william">William</character>,</speech> he said.</p>
            <p><speech ref="william">It's a fine <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >house</scary_word>,</speech> answered <character ref="william"
                    >William</character>, raking the embers together as he spoke and throwing some
                wood upon them; <speech ref="william">but, like many a good family, it has come
                        <scary_word pos="adv" scale="1">down</scary_word> in the world.</speech></p>
            <p>There were four <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">windows</scary_word> in the room,
                shuttered close; they had <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">deep</scary_word>, low
                seats, suggestive of pleasant days gone by; when, well-curtained and well-cushioned,
                they formed snug retreats for the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >children</scary_word>, and sometimes for adults also; there was no furniture
                left, unless an oaken settle beside the hearth, and a large mirror let into the
                panelling at the opposite end of the apartment, with a <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="0">black</scary_word> marble console table beneath it, could be so
                considered; but the <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i">very</scary_word> absence of
                chairs and tables enabled the magnificent proportions of the chamber to be seen to
                full advantage, and there wa Coultons nothing to distract the attention from the
                ornamented ceiling, the panelled walls, the old-world chimney-piece so quaintly
                carved, and the fireplace lined with tiles, each one of which contained a picture of
                some scriptural or allegorical subject.</p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">Had you been staying on here, <character ref="william"
                        >William</character>,</speech> said <character ref="grahamCoulton"
                    >Coulton</character>, flinging himself wearily on the settle, <speech
                    ref="grahamCoulton">I'd have asked you to let me stop where I am for the
                        <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">night</scary_word>.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="william">If you can make shift, sir, there is nothing as I am aware of
                    to prevent you stopping,</speech> answered the man, fanning the wood into a
                flame. <speech ref="william">I shan't take the key back to the landlord till
                    tomorrow, and this would be better for you than the <scary_word pos="adj"
                        scale="0">cold</scary_word> streets at any rate.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">Do you really mean what you say?</speech> asked the other
                eagerly. <speech ref="grahamCoulton">I should be thankful to lie here; I feel
                        <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">dead</scary_word> beat.</speech></p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="william">Then stay, <character ref="grahamCoulton">Master
                        Graham</character>, and welcome. I'll fetch a basket of coals I was going to
                    put in the van, and make up a good <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                        >fire</scary_word>, so that you can warm yourself then I must run round to
                    the other <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">house</scary_word> for a minute or
                    two, but it's not far, and I'll be back as soon as ever I can.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">Thank you, <character ref="william">William</character>;
                    you were always good to me,</speech> said the young man gratefully. <speech
                    ref="grahamCoulton">This is delightful,</speech> and he stretched his numbed
                hands over the blazing wood, and looked round the room with a satisfied smile.</p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">I did not expect to get into such quarters,</speech> he
                remarked, as his friend in need reappeared, carrying a half-bushel basket full of
                coals, with which he proceeded to make up a roaring <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >fire</scary_word>. <speech ref="grahamCoulton">I am sure the last thing I could
                    have imagined was meeting with anyone I knew in Vauxhall Walk.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="william">Where were you coming from, <character ref="grahamCoulton"
                        >Master Graham</character>?</speech> asked <character ref="william"
                    >William</character>
                <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0">curiously</scary_word>.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="grahamCoulton">From <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">old</scary_word>
                    Melfield's. I was at his school once, you know, and he has now retired, and is
                    living upon the proceeds of years of robbery in Kennington Oval. I thought,
                    perhaps he would lend me a pound, or offer me a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                        >night</scary_word>'s lodging, or even a glass of wine; but, oh dear, no. He
                    took the moral tone, and observed he could have nothing to say to a son who
                    defied his father's authority. He gave me plenty of advice, but nothing else,
                    and showed me out into the rain with a bland courtesy, for which I could have
                    struck him.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><character ref="william">William</character>
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0">muttered</scary_word> something under his breath
                which was not a blessing, and added aloud: <speech ref="william">You are better
                    here, sir, I think, at any rate. I'll be back in less than half an
                    hour.</speech></p>
            <p>Left to himself, young <character ref="grahamCoulton">Coulton</character> took off
                his coat, and shifting the settle a little, hung it over the end to dry. With his
                handkerchief he rubbed some of the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">wet</scary_word>
                out of his hair; then, perfectly exhausted, he lay <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0"
                    >down</scary_word> before the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">fire</scary_word>
                and, pillowing his head on his arm, fell fast asleep.</p>
            <p>He was awakened nearly an hour afterwards by the sound of someone gently stirring the
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">fire</scary_word> and moving quietly about the
                room. Starting into a sitting posture, he looked around him, bewildered for a
                moment, and then, recognising his humble friend, said laughingly:</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="grahamCoulton">I had <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0">lost</scary_word>
                    myself; I could not imagine where I was.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="william">I am sorry to see you here, sir,</speech> was the reply;
                    <speech ref="william">but <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0">still</scary_word>
                    this is better than being out of doors. It has come on a <scary_word pos="adj"
                        scale="1">nasty</scary_word>
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">night</scary_word>. I brought a rug round with
                    me that, perhaps, you would wrap yourself in.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">I wish, at the same time, you had brought me something to
                    eat,</speech> said the young man, laughing.</p>
            <p><speech ref="william">Are you hungry, then, sir?</speech> asked <character
                    ref="william">William</character>, in a tone of concern.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="grahamCoulton">Yes; I have had nothing to eat since breakfast. The
                    governor and I commenced rowing the minute we sat <scary_word pos="adv"
                        scale="0">down</scary_word> to luncheon, and I rose and left the table. But
                    hunger does not signify; I am dry and warm, and can forget the other matter in
                    sleep.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="william">And it's too late now to buy anything,</speech> soliloquised
                the man; <speech ref="william">the shops are all shut long ago. Do you think,
                    sir,</speech> he added, brightening, <speech ref="william">you could manage some
                    bread and cheese?</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">Do I think—I should call it a perfect feast,</speech>
                answered <character ref="grahamCoulton">Graham Coulton</character>. <speech
                    ref="grahamCoulton">But never mind about food tonight, <character ref="william"
                        >William</character>; you have had <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                        >trouble</scary_word> enough, and to spare, already.</speech></p>
            <p><character ref="william">William</character>'s only answer was to dart to the door
                and run downstairs. Presently he reappeared, carrying in one hand bread and cheese
                wrapped up in paper, and in the other a pewter measure full of beer.</p>
            <p><speech ref="william">It's the best I could do, sir,</speech> he said apologetically.
                    <speech ref="william">I had to beg this from the landlady.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">Here's to her good health!</speech> exclaimed the young
                fellow gaily, taking a long pull at the tankard. <speech ref="grahamCoulton">That
                    tastes better than champagne in my father's <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                        >house</scary_word>.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="william">Won't he be uneasy about you?</speech> ventured <character
                    ref="william">William</character>, who, having by this time emptied the coals,
                was now seated on the inverted basket, looking <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0"
                    >wistfully</scary_word> at the relish with which the son of the former master
                was eating his bread and cheese.</p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">No,</speech> was the decided answer. <speech
                    ref="grahamCoulton">When he hears it pouring cats and dogs he will only hope I
                    am out in the deluge, and say a good drenching will cool my pride.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="william">I do not think you are right there,</speech> remarked the
                man.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="grahamCoulton">But I am sure I am. My father always <scary_word
                        pos="verb" scale="0">hated</scary_word> me, as he <scary_word pos="verb"
                        scale="0">hated</scary_word> my mother.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="william">Begging your pardon, sir; he was over fond of your
                    mother.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="grahamCoulton">If you had heard what he said about her today, you might
                    find reason to alter your opinion. He told me I resembled her in mind as well as
                    body; that I was a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">coward</scary_word>, a
                    simpleton, and a hypocrite.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="william">He did not mean it, sir.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">He did, every word. He does think I am a <scary_word
                        pos="noun" scale="0">coward</scary_word>, because I—I—</speech> And the
                young fellow broke into a passion of hysterical tears.</p>
            <p><speech ref="william">I don't half like leaving you here <scary_word pos="adj"
                        scale="1">alone</scary_word>,</speech> said <character ref="william"
                    >William</character>, glancing round the room with a quick <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="1">trouble</scary_word> in his <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="1">eyes</scary_word>; <speech ref="william">but I have no place fit to
                    ask you to stop, and I am forced to go myself, because I am <scary_word
                        pos="noun" scale="0">night</scary_word> watchman, and must be on at twelve
                    o'clock.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">I shall be right enough,</speech> was the answer. <speech
                    ref="grahamCoulton">Only I mustn't talk any more of my father. Tell me about
                    yourself, <character ref="william">William</character>. How did you manage to
                    get such a big <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">house</scary_word>, and why are
                    you leaving it?</speech></p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="william">The landlord put me in charge, sir; and it was my wife's fancy
                    not to like it.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="grahamCoulton">Why did she not like it?</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="william">She felt <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">desolate</scary_word>
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">alone</scary_word> with the <scary_word
                        pos="noun" scale="0">children</scary_word> at <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="1">night</scary_word>,</speech> answered <character ref="william"
                    >William</character>, turning away his head; then added, next minute: <speech
                    ref="william">Now, sir, if you think I can do no more for you, I had best be
                    off. Time's getting on. I'll look round tomorrow morning.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">Good <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >night</scary_word>,</speech> said the young fellow, stretching out his hand,
                which the other took as freely and frankly as it was offered. <speech
                    ref="grahamCoulton">What should I have done this <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="0">evening</scary_word> if I had not chanced to meet
                you?</speech></p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="william">I don't think there is much chance in the world, <character
                        ref="grahamCoulton">Master Graham</character>,' was the quiet answer. 'I do
                    hope you will rest well, and not be the worse for your wetting.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">No <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">fear</scary_word> of
                    that,</speech> was the rejoinder, and the next minute the young man found
                himself all <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">alone</scary_word> in the <scary_word
                    pos="adj" scale="1">Old</scary_word> House in Vauxhall Walk.</p>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
            <chapTitle>Chapter Two</chapTitle>
            <p>Lying on the settle, with the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">fire</scary_word>
                burnt out, and the room in total <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >darkness</scary_word>, <character ref="grahamCoulton">Graham
                    Coulton</character>
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0">dreamed</scary_word> a <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="1">curious</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">dream</scary_word>. He thought he awoke from
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">deep</scary_word> slumber to find a log
                smouldering away upon the hearth, and the mirror at the end of the apartment
                reflecting fitful gleams of <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">light</scary_word>. He
                could not understand how it came to pass that, far away as he was from the glass, he
                was able to see everything in it; but he resigned himself to the difficulty without
                astonishment, as people generally do in <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >dreams</scary_word>.</p>
            <plot point="haunting"/>
            <p>Neither did he feel surprised when he beheld the outline of a female figure seated
                beside the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">fire</scary_word>, engaged in picking
                something out of her lap and dropping it with a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="3"
                    >despairing</scary_word> gesture.</p>
            <p>He heard the mellow sound of gold, and knew she was lifting and dropping sovereigns,
                he turned a little so as to see the person engaged in such a singular and
                meaningless manner, and found that, where there had been no chair on the previous
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">night</scary_word>, there was a chair now, on
                which was seated an <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">old</scary_word>, <scary_word
                    pos="adj" scale="2">wrinkled</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">hag</scary_word>, her clothes <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="1">poor</scary_word> and <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                    >ragged</scary_word>, a mob cap barely covering her <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="1">scant</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">white</scary_word> hair, her cheeks <scary_word
                    pos="adj" scale="2">sunken</scary_word>, her nose <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="2">hooked</scary_word>, her fingers more like <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="3">talons</scary_word> than aught else as they dived <scary_word
                    pos="adv" scale="0">down</scary_word> into the heap of gold, portions of which
                they lifted but to scatter <scary_word pos="adv" scale="2"
                >mournfully</scary_word>.</p>
            <p><speech ref="missTynan">Oh! my <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">lost</scary_word>
                    life,</speech> she <scary_word pos="verb" scale="3">moaned</scary_word>, in a
                voice of the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">bitterest</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">anguish</scary_word>. <speech ref="missTynan">Oh!
                    my <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">lost</scary_word> life—for one day, for one
                    hour of it again!</speech></p>
            <p>Out of the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">darkness</scary_word>—out of the corner
                of the room where the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">shadows</scary_word> lay
                deepest—out from the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">gloom</scary_word> abiding
                near the door—out from the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">dreary</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">night</scary_word>, with their sodden feet and
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">wet</scary_word> dripping from their heads, came
                the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">old</scary_word> men and the young <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="0">children</scary_word>, the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2"
                    >worn</scary_word> women and the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0"
                    >weary</scary_word> hearts, whose misery that gold might have relieved, but
                whose wretchedness it mocked.</p>
            <p>Round that miser, who once sat gloating as she now sat lamenting, they crowded—all
                those <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">pale</scary_word>, <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="2">sad</scary_word> shapes—the aged of days, the infant of hours, the
                sobbing outcast, honest poverty, repentant vice; but one low <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="3">cry</scary_word> proceeded from those <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2"
                    >pale</scary_word> lips—a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">cry</scary_word> for
                help she might have given, but which she withheld.</p>
            <p>They <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1">closed</scary_word> about her, all together, as
                they had done singly in life; they prayed, they sobbed, they <scary_word pos="verb"
                    scale="1">entreated</scary_word>; with <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2"
                    >haggard</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">eyes</scary_word> the figure regarded the
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">poor</scary_word> she had repulsed, the
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">children</scary_word> against whose <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="1">cry</scary_word> she had <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0"
                    >closed</scary_word> her ears, the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                    >old</scary_word> people she had suffered to starve and <scary_word pos="verb"
                    scale="1">die</scary_word> for want of what would have been the merest trifle to
                her; then, with a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">terrible</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">scream</scary_word>, she raised her lean arms above
                her head, and sank <scary_word pos="adv" scale="1">down</scary_word>—<scary_word
                    pos="adv" scale="1">down</scary_word>—the gold scattering as it fell out of her
                lap, and rolling along the floor, till its gleam was <scary_word pos="verb"
                    scale="0">lost</scary_word> in the outer <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2"
                    >darkness</scary_word> beyond.</p>
            <p>Then <character ref="grahamCoulton">Graham Coulton</character> awoke in good earnest,
                with the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">perspiration</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1">oozing</scary_word> from every pore, with a
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">fear</scary_word> and an <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="2">agony</scary_word> upon him such as he had never before felt in all
                his existence, and with the sound of the heart-rending <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="2">cry</scary_word>—<speech ref="missTynan">Oh! my <scary_word pos="adj"
                        scale="1">lost</scary_word> life</speech>—<scary_word pos="adv" scale="0"
                    >still</scary_word> ringing in his ears.</p>
            <p>Mingled with all, too, there seemed to have been some lesson for him which he had
                forgotten, that, try as he would, eluded his memory, and which, in the <scary_word
                    pos="mod" scale="i">very</scary_word> act of waking, glided away.</p>
            <p>He lay for a little thinking about all this, and then, <scary_word pos="adv"
                    scale="0">still</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">heavy</scary_word> with sleep, retraced his way into
                dreamland once more.</p>
            <p>It was natural, perhaps, that, mingling with the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                    >strange</scary_word> fantasies which follow in the train of <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="1">night</scary_word> and <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >darkness</scary_word>, the former vision should recur, and the young man ere
                long found himself toiling through scene after scene wherein the figure of the woman
                he had seen seated beside a dying <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">fire</scary_word>
                held principal place.</p>
            <p>He saw her walking <scary_word pos="adv" scale="1">slowly</scary_word> across the
                floor munching a dry crust—she who could have purchased all the luxuries wealth can
                command; on the hearth, contemplating her, stood a man of commanding presence,
                dressed in the fashion of long ago. In his <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >eyes</scary_word> there was a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2"
                    >dark</scary_word> look of anger, on his lips a curling smile of disgust, and
                somehow, even in his sleep, the dreamer understood it was the ancestor to the
                descendant he beheld—that the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word>
                put to mean uses in which he lay had never so far descended from its high estate, as
                the woman possessed of so pitiful a soul, <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1"
                    >contaminated</scary_word> with the most <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                    >despicable</scary_word> and <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                    >insidious</scary_word> vice <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">poor</scary_word>
                humanity knows, for all other vices seem to have connection with the <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="1">flesh</scary_word>, but the greed of the miser eats into
                the <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i">very</scary_word> soul.</p>
            <p><scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">Filthy</scary_word> of person, <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="2">repulsive</scary_word> to look at, hard of heart as she was, he yet
                beheld another <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">phantom</scary_word>, which, coming
                into the room, met her almost on the threshold, taking her by the hand, and
                pleading, as it seemed, for assistance. He could not hear all that passed, but a
                word now and then fell upon his ear. Some talk of former days; some mention of a
                fair young mother—an appeal, as it seemed, to a time when they were tiny brother and
                sister, and the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">accursed</scary_word> greed for gold
                had not divided them. All in vain; the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2"
                    >hag</scary_word> only answered him as she had answered the <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="0">children</scary_word>, and the young girls, and the
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">old</scary_word> people in his former vision.
                Her heart was as invulnerable to natural affection as it had proved to human
                sympathy. He begged, as it appeared, for aid to avert some <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="1">bitter</scary_word> misfortune or <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                    >terrible</scary_word> disgrace, and adamant might have been found more yielding
                to his prayer. Then the figure standing on the hearth changed to an angel, which
                folded its wings <scary_word pos="adv" scale="2">mournfully</scary_word> over its
                face, and the man, with bowed head, <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0"
                    >slowly</scary_word> left the room.</p>
            <p>Even as he did so the scene changed again; it was <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >night</scary_word> once more, and the miser wended her way upstairs. From
                below, <character ref="grahamCoulton">Graham Coulton</character> fancied he watched
                her toiling wearily from step to step. She had aged <scary_word pos="adv" scale="2"
                    >strangely</scary_word> since the previous scenes. She moved with difficulty; it
                seemed the greatest exertion for her to <scary_word pos="verb" scale="3"
                    >creep</scary_word> from step to step, her skinny hand traversing the balusters
                with slow and <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">painful</scary_word> deliberateness.
                Fascinated, the young man's <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">eyes</scary_word>
                followed the progress of that feeble, decrepit woman. She was solitary in a
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">desolate</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">house</scary_word>, with a <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="1">deeper</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">blackness</scary_word> than the <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="2">darkness</scary_word> of <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >night</scary_word> waiting to engulf her.</p>
            <p>It seemed to <character ref="grahamCoulton">Graham Coulton</character> that after
                that he lay for a time in a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">still</scary_word>,
                dreamless sleep, upon awaking from which he found himself entering a chamber as
                sordid and unclean in its appointments as the woman of his previous vision had been
                in her person. The <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">poorest</scary_word> labourer's
                wife would have gathered more comforts around her than that room contained. A
                four-poster bedstead without hangings of any kind—a blind drawn up awry—an
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">old</scary_word> carpet covered with dust, and
                dirt on the floor—a rickety washstand with all the paint <scary_word pos="verb"
                    scale="0">worn</scary_word> off it—an ancient mahogany dressing-table, and a
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">cracked</scary_word> glass spotted all over—were
                all the objects he could at first discern, looking at the room through that
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">dim</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">light</scary_word> which oftentimes obtains in
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">dreams</scary_word>.</p>
            <p>By degrees, however, he perceived the outline of someone lying huddled on the bed.
                Drawing nearer, he found it was that of the person whose <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="2">dreadful</scary_word> presence seemed to pervade the <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="2">house</scary_word>. What a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="3"
                    >terrible</scary_word> sight she looked, with her <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="1">thin</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">white</scary_word> locks scattered over the pillow,
                with what were mere remnants of blankets gathered about her shoulders, with her
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="3">claw-like</scary_word> fingers clutching the
                clothes, as though even in sleep she was guarding her gold!</p>
            <p>An <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">awful</scary_word> and a <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="2">repulsive</scary_word> spectacle, but not with half the <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="1">terror</scary_word> in it of that which followed. Even as
                the young man looked he heard <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">stealthy</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">footsteps</scary_word> on the stairs. Then he saw
                first one man and then his fellow <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2"
                    >steal</scary_word> cautiously into the room. Another second, and the pair stood
                beside the bed, <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">murder</scary_word> in their
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">eyes</scary_word>.</p>
            <p><character ref="grahamCoulton">Graham Coulton</character> tried to shout—tried to
                move, but the deterrent power which exists in <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >dreams</scary_word> only tied his tongue <character ref="william"
                    >William</character> and <scary_word pos="verb" scale="3">paralysed</scary_word>
                his limbs. He could but hear and look, and what he heard and saw was this: aroused
                suddenly from sleep, the woman started, only to receive a blow from one of the
                ruffians, whose fellow followed his lead by <scary_phrase><scary_word pos="verb"
                        scale="3">plunging</scary_word> a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3"
                        >knife</scary_word> into her breast</scary_phrase>.</p>
            <p>Then, with a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="3">gurgling</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">scream</scary_word>, she fell back on the bed, and
                at the same moment, with a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">cry</scary_word>,
                    <character ref="grahamCoulton">Graham Coulton</character> again awoke, to thank
                heaven it was but an illusion.</p>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
            <chapTitle>Chapter Three</chapTitle>
            <p><speech ref="william">I hope you slept well, sir.</speech> It was <character
                    ref="william">William</character>, who, coming into the hall with the sunlight
                of a fine bright morning streaming after him, asked this question: <speech
                    ref="william">Had you a good <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >night</scary_word>'s rest?</speech></p>
            <p><character ref="grahamCoulton">Graham Coulton</character> laughed, and answered:
                    <speech ref="grahamCoulton">Why, faith, I was somewhat in the case of Paddy,
                    “who could not slape for dhraming”. I slept well enough, I suppose, but whether
                    it was in consequence of the row with my dad, or the hard bed, or the
                    cheese—most likely the bread and cheese so late at <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="0">night</scary_word>—I <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                        >dreamt</scary_word> all the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                        >night</scary_word> long, the most extraordinary <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="1">dreams</scary_word>. Some <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                        >old</scary_word> woman kept cropping up, and I saw her <scary_word
                        pos="verb" scale="3">murdered</scary_word>.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="william">You don't say that, sir?</speech> said <character ref="william"
                    >William</character>
                <scary_word pos="adv" scale="1">nervously</scary_word>.</p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">I do, indeed,</speech> was the reply. <speech
                    ref="grahamCoulton">However, that is all gone and past. I have been <scary_word
                        pos="adv" scale="0">down</scary_word> in the kitchen and had a good wash,
                    and I am as fresh as a daisy, and as hungry as a hunter; and, oh, <character
                        ref="william">William</character>, can you get me any
                breakfast?</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="william">Certainly, Master Graham. I have brought round a kettle, and I
                    will make the water boil immediately. I suppose, sir</speech>—this
                    tentatively—<speech ref="william">you'll be going home today?</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">Home!</speech>
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0">repeated</scary_word> the young man. <speech
                    ref="grahamCoulton">Decidedly not. I'll never go home again till I return with
                    some medal hung to my coat, or a leg or arm cut off. I've thought it all out,
                        <character ref="william">William</character>. I'll go and enlist. There's a
                    talk of war; and, living or <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">dead</scary_word>,
                    my father shall have reason to retract his opinion about my being a <scary_word
                        pos="noun" scale="0">coward</scary_word>.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="william">I am sure the admiral never thought you anything of the sort,
                    sir,</speech> said <character ref="william">William</character>. <speech
                    ref="william">Why, you have the pluck of ten!</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">Not before him,</speech> answered the young fellow
                sadly.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="william">You'll do nothing rash, <character ref="grahamCoulton">Master
                        Graham</character>; you won't go 'listing, or aught of that sort, in your
                    anger?</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">If I do not, what is to become of me?</speech> asked the
                other. <speech ref="grahamCoulton">I cannot dig—to beg I am ashamed. Why, but for
                    you, I should not have had a roof over my head last <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="0">night</scary_word>.</speech></p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="william">Not much of a roof, I am <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0"
                        >afraid</scary_word>, sir.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">Not much of a roof!</speech>
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0">repeated</scary_word> the young man. <speech
                    ref="grahamCoulton">Why, who could desire a better? What a capital room this
                    is,' he went on, looking around the apartment, where <character ref="william"
                        >William</character> was now kindling a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                        >fire</scary_word>; 'one might dine twenty people here easily!</speech></p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="william">If you think so well of the place, <character
                        ref="grahamCoulton">Master Graham</character>, you might stay here for a
                    while, till you have made up your mind what you are going to do. The landlord
                    won't make any objection, I am <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i">very</scary_word>
                    sure.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="grahamCoulton">Oh! nonsense; he would want a long rent for a
                        <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">house</scary_word> like this.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="william">I dare say; if he could get it,</speech> was <character
                    ref="william">William</character>'s significant answer.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="grahamCoulton">What do you mean? Won't the place let?</speech>
            </p>
            <plot point="history"/>
            <p>
                <speech ref="william">No, sir. I did not tell you last <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="0">night</scary_word>, but there was a <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="3">murder</scary_word> done here, and people are shy of the
                        <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">house</scary_word> ever since.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="grahamCoulton">A <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">murder</scary_word>!
                    What sort of a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">murder</scary_word>? Who was
                        <scary_word pos="verb" scale="3">murdered</scary_word>?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="william">A woman, <character ref="grahamCoulton">Master
                        Graham</character>—the landlord's sister; she lived here all <scary_word
                        pos="adj" scale="0">alone</scary_word>, and was supposed to have money.
                    Whether she had or not, she was found <scary_word pos="adj" scale="3"
                        >dead</scary_word> from a stab in her breast, and if there ever was any
                    money, it must have been taken at the same time, for none ever was found in the
                        <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">house</scary_word> from that day to
                    this.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">Was that the reason your wife would not stop
                    here?</speech> asked the young man, leaning against the mantelshelf, and looking
                thoughtfully <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0">down</scary_word> on <character
                    ref="william">William</character>.</p>
            <p><speech ref="william">Yes, sir. She could not stand it any longer; she got that
                        <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">thin</scary_word> and <scary_word pos="adj"
                        scale="1">nervous</scary_word> no one would have <scary_word pos="verb"
                        scale="0">believed</scary_word> it possible; she never saw anything, but she
                    said she heard <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">footsteps</scary_word> and
                        <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">voices</scary_word>, and then when she
                    walked through the hall, or up the staircase, someone always seemed to be
                        <scary_word pos="verb" scale="3">following</scary_word> her. We put the
                        <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">children</scary_word> to sleep in that big
                    room you had last <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">night</scary_word>, and they
                    declared they often saw an <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">old</scary_word>
                    woman sitting by the hearth. Nothing ever came my way,</speech> finished
                    <character ref="william">William</character>, with a laugh; <speech
                    ref="william">I was always ready to go to sleep the minute my head touched the
                    pillow.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">Were not the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                        >murderers</scary_word> discovered?</speech> asked Graham Coulton.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="william">No, sir; the landlord, <character ref="mrTynan">Miss Tynan's
                        brother</character>, had always lain under the suspicion of it—<scary_word
                        pos="mod" scale="i">quite</scary_word> wrongfully, I am <scary_word
                        pos="mod" scale="i">very</scary_word> sure—but he will never clear himself
                    now. It was known he came and asked her for help a day or two before the
                        <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">murder</scary_word>, and it was also known
                    he was able within a week or two to weather whatever <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="0">trouble</scary_word> had been harassing him. Then, you see, the
                    money was never found; and, altogether, people scarce knew what to
                    think.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">Humph!</speech> ejaculated <character ref="grahamCoulton"
                    >Graham Coulton</character>, and he took a few turns up and <scary_word
                    pos="adv" scale="0">down</scary_word> the apartment. <speech ref="grahamCoulton"
                    >Could I go and see this landlord?</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="william">Surely, sir, if you had a hat,</speech> answered <character
                    ref="william">William</character>, with such a serious decorum that the young
                man burst out laughing.</p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">That is an obstacle, certainly,</speech> he remarked,
                    <speech ref="grahamCoulton">and I must make a note do instead. I have a pencil
                    in my pocket, so here goes.</speech></p>
            <p>Within half an hour from the dispatch of that note <character ref="william"
                    >William</character> was back again with a sovereign; the landlord's
                compliments, and he would be much obliged if <character ref="grahamCoulton">Mr
                    Coulton</character> could 'step round'.</p>
            <p><speech ref="william">You'll do nothing rash, sir,</speech>
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1">entreated</scary_word>
                <character ref="william">William</character>.</p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">Why, man,</speech> answered the young fellow, <speech
                    ref="grahamCoulton">one may as well be picked off by a <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="1">ghost</scary_word> as a bullet. What is there to be <scary_word
                        pos="adj" scale="1">afraid</scary_word> of?</speech></p>
            <p><character ref="william">William</character> only shook his head. He did not think
                his young master was made of the stuff likely to remain <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="0">alone</scary_word> in a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2"
                    >haunted</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">house</scary_word> and solve the <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="1">mystery</scary_word> it assuredly contained by dint of his
                own unassisted endeavours. And yet when <character ref="grahamCoulton">Graham
                    Coulton</character> came out of the landlord's <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >house</scary_word> he looked more bright and gay than usual, and walked up the
                Lambeth road to the place where <character ref="william">William</character> awaited
                his return, humming an <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">air</scary_word> as he paced
                along.</p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">We have settled the matter,</speech> he said. <speech
                    ref="grahamCoulton">And now if the dad wants his son for Christmas, it will
                        <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">trouble</scary_word> him to find
                    him.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="william">Don't say that, Master Graham, don't,</speech>
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0">entreated</scary_word> the man, with a <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="1">shiver</scary_word>; <speech ref="william">maybe after all
                    it would have been better if you had never happened to chance upon Vauxhall
                    Walk.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">Don't croak, <character ref="william"
                    >William</character>,</speech> answered the young man; <speech
                    ref="grahamCoulton">if it was not the best day's work I ever did for myself I'm
                    a Dutchman.</speech></p>
            <p>During the whole of that forenoon and afternoon, <character ref="grahamCoulton"
                    >Graham Coulton</character> searched diligently for the missing treasure
                    <character ref="mrTynan">Mr Tynan</character> assured him had never been
                discovered. Youth is confident and self- opinionated, and this fresh explorer felt
                satisfied that, though others had failed, he would be successful. On the second
                floor he found one door <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">locked</scary_word>, but he
                did not pay much attention to that at the moment, as he <scary_word pos="verb"
                    scale="0">believed</scary_word> if there was anything concealed it was more
                likely to be found in the lower than the upper part of the <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="0">house</scary_word>. Late into the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >evening</scary_word> he pursued his researches in the kitchen and cellars and
                old-fashioned cupboards, of which the basement had an abundance.</p>
            <p>It was nearly eleven, when, engaged in poking about amongst the <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="0">empty</scary_word> bins of a wine cellar as large as a family vault,
                he suddenly felt a<scary_phrase><scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">rush</scary_word>
                    of <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">cold</scary_word>
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">air</scary_word></scary_phrase> at his back.
                Moving, his candle was <scary_word pos="adv" scale="1">instantly</scary_word>
                extinguished, and in the <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i">very</scary_word> moment of
                being left in <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">darkness</scary_word> he saw,
                standing in the doorway, a woman, resembling her who had <scary_word pos="verb"
                    scale="2">haunted</scary_word> his <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >dreams</scary_word> overnight.</p>
            <p>He rushed with outstretched hands to <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1"
                    >seize</scary_word> her, but clutched only <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >air</scary_word>. He relit his candle, and closely examined the basement,
                shutting off communication with the ground floor ere doing so. All in vain. Not a
                trace could he find of living creature—not a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >window</scary_word> was open—not a door unbolted.</p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">It is <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i">very</scary_word>
                    odd,</speech> he thought, as, after securely fastening the door at the top of
                the staircase, he searched the whole upper portion of the <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="0">house</scary_word>, with the exception of the one room mentioned.</p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">I must get the key of that tomorrow,</speech> he decided,
                standing <scary_word pos="adv" scale="1">gloomily</scary_word> with his back to the
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">fire</scary_word> and his <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="0">eyes</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0">wandering</scary_word> about the drawing-room,
                where he had once again taken up his abode.</p>
            <p>Even as the thought passed through his mind, he saw standing in the open doorway a
                woman with <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">white</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">dishevelled</scary_word> hair, clad in mean
                garments, <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">ragged</scary_word> and <scary_word
                    pos="adj" scale="2">dirty</scary_word>. She lifted her hand and shook it at him
                with a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="3">menacing</scary_word> gesture, and then, just
                as he was darting towards her, a wonderful thing occurred.</p>
            <p>From behind the great mirror there glided a second female figure, at the sight of
                which the first turned and fled, littering <scary_word pos="adj" scale="3"
                    >piercing</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">shrieks</scary_word> as the other followed her from
                storey to storey.</p>
            <p>Sick almost with <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">terror</scary_word>, <character
                    ref="grahamCoulton">Graham Coulton</character> watched the <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="3">dreadful</scary_word> pair as they fled upstairs past the <scary_word
                    pos="adj" scale="0">locked</scary_word> room to the top of the <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="2">house</scary_word>.</p>
            <p>It was a few minutes before he recovered his self-possession. When he did so, and
                searched the upper apartments, he found them totally <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                    >empty</scary_word>.</p>
            <p>That <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">night</scary_word>, ere lying <scary_word
                    pos="adv" scale="0">down</scary_word> before the <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="0">fire</scary_word>, he carefully <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0"
                    >locked</scary_word> and bolted the drawing-room door; before he did more he
                drew the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">heavy</scary_word> settle in front of it,
                so that if the lock were forced no entrance could be effected without considerable
                noise.</p>
            <p>For some time he lay awake, then dropped into a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0"
                    >deep</scary_word> sleep, from which he was awakened suddenly by a noise as if
                of something scuffling <scary_word pos="adv" scale="2">stealthily</scary_word>
                behind the wainscot. He raised himself on his elbow and listened, and, to his
                consternation, beheld seated at the opposite side of the hearth the same woman he
                had seen before in his <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">dreams</scary_word>,
                lamenting over her gold.</p>
            <p>The <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">fire</scary_word> was not <scary_word pos="mod"
                    scale="i">quite</scary_word> out, and at that moment shot up a last tongue of
                flame. By the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">light</scary_word>, transient as it
                was, he saw that the figure pressed a <scary_word pos="adv" scale="2"
                    >ghostly</scary_word> finger to its lips, and by the turn of its head and the
                attitude of its body seemed to be listening.</p>
            <p>He listened also—indeed, he was too much <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2"
                    >frightened</scary_word> to do aught else; more and more distinct grew the
                sounds which had aroused him, a <scary_phrase><scary_word pos="adj" scale="2"
                        >stealthy</scary_word>
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">rustling</scary_word></scary_phrase> coming
                nearer and nearer—up and up it seemed, behind the wainscot.</p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">It is rats,</speech> thought the young man, though,
                indeed, his teeth were almost chattering in his head with <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="3">fear</scary_word>. But then in a moment he saw what disabused him of
                that idea—the gleam of a candle or lamp through a crack in the panelling. He tried
                to rise, he strove to shout—all in vain; and, sinking <scary_word pos="adv"
                    scale="0">down</scary_word>, remembered nothing more till he awoke to find the
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">grey</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">light</scary_word> of an early morning <scary_word
                    pos="verb" scale="0">stealing</scary_word> through one of the <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="0">shutters</scary_word> he had left partially unclosed.</p>
            <p>For hours after his breakfast, which he scarcely touched, long after <character
                    ref="william">William</character> had left him at mid-day, <character
                    ref="grahamCoulton">Graham Coulton</character>, having in the morning made a
                long and close survey of the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">house</scary_word>,
                sat thinking before the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">fire</scary_word>, then,
                apparently having made up his mind, he put on the hat he had bought, and went
                out.</p>
            <p>When he returned the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">evening</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">shadows</scary_word> were <scary_word pos="verb"
                    scale="1">darkening</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0">down</scary_word>, but the pavements were full of
                people going marketing, for it was Christmas Eve, and all who had money to spend
                seemed bent on shopping.</p>
            <p>It was terribly <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">dreary</scary_word> inside the
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">old</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word> that <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="1">night</scary_word>. Through the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                    >deserted</scary_word> rooms <character ref="grahamCoulton">Graham</character>
                could feel that <scary_word pos="adv" scale="2">ghostly</scary_word> semblance was
                    <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2">wandering</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="adv" scale="2">mournfully</scary_word>. When he turned his back he
                knew she was flitting from the mirror to the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >fire</scary_word>, from the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">fire</scary_word>
                to the mirror; but he was not <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">afraid</scary_word> of
                her now—he was far more <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">afraid</scary_word> of
                another matter he had taken in hand that day.</p>
            <p>The <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">horror</scary_word> of the <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="2">silent</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word> grew and grew upon him. He could
                hear the beating of his own heart in the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                    >dead</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">quietude</scary_word> which reigned from garret to
                cellar.</p>
            <p>At last <character ref="william">William</character> came; but the young man said
                nothing to him of what was in his mind. He talked to him cheerfully and hopefully
                enough—wondered where his father would think he had got to, and hoped <character
                    ref="mrTynan">Mr Tynan</character> might send him some Christmas pudding. Then
                the man said it was time for him to go, and, when <character ref="grahamCoulton">Mr
                    Coulton</character> went downstairs to the hall-door, remarked the key was not
                in it.</p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">No,</speech> was the answer, <speech ref="grahamCoulton"
                    >I took it out today, to oil it.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="william">It wanted oiling,</speech> agreed <character ref="william"
                    >William</character>, <speech ref="william">for it worked terribly
                    stiff.</speech> Having uttered which truism he departed.</p>
            <p>Very <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0">slowly</scary_word> the young man retraced his
                way to the drawing-room, where he only paused to lock the door on the outside; then
                taking off his boots he went up to the top of the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >house</scary_word>, where, entering the front attic, he waited patiently in
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">darkness</scary_word> and in silence.</p>
            <p>It was a long time, or at least it seemed long to him, before he heard the same sound
                which had aroused him on the previous <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >night</scary_word>—a <scary_phrase><scary_word pos="adj" scale="2"
                        >stealthy</scary_word>
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">rustling</scary_word></scary_phrase>—then
                        a<scary_phrase><scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">rush</scary_word> of
                        <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">cold</scary_word>
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">air</scary_word></scary_phrase>—then cautious
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">footsteps</scary_word>—then the quiet opening
                of a door below.</p>
            <p>It did not take as long in action as it has required to tell. In a moment the young
                man was out on the landing and had <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0"
                    >closed</scary_word> a portion of the panelling on the wall which stood open;
                noiselessly he crept back to the attic <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >window</scary_word>, unlatched it, and sprung a <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="0">rattle</scary_word>, the sound of which <scary_word pos="verb"
                    scale="1">echoed</scary_word> far and near through the <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="1">deserted</scary_word> streets, then rushing <scary_word pos="adv"
                    scale="0">down</scary_word> the stairs, he encountered a man who, darting past
                him, made for the landing above; but perceiving the way of escape <scary_word
                    pos="adj" scale="1">closed</scary_word>, fled <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0"
                    >down</scary_word> again, to find <character ref="grahamCoulton"
                    >Graham</character> struggling desperately with his fellow.</p>
            <p><speech ref="intruder">Give him the knife—come along,</speech> he said <scary_word
                    pos="adv" scale="3">savagely</scary_word>; and next <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="1">instant</scary_word>
                <character ref="grahamCoulton">Graham</character>
                <scary_phrase>felt something like a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">hot</scary_word>
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">iron</scary_word> through his
                    shoulder</scary_phrase>, and then heard a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >thud</scary_word>, as one of the men, tripping in his rapid flight, fell from
                the top of the stairs to the bottom.</p>
            <p>At the same moment there came a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">crash</scary_word>,
                as if the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word> was <scary_word
                    pos="verb" scale="2">falling</scary_word>, and <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                    >faint</scary_word>, <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">sick</scary_word>, and
                    <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2">bleeding</scary_word>, young <character
                    ref="grahamCoulton">Coulton</character> lay <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                    >insensible</scary_word> on the threshold of the room where <character
                    ref="missTynan">Miss Tynan</character> had been <scary_word pos="verb" scale="3"
                    >murdered</scary_word>.</p>
            <p>When he recovered he was in the dining-room, and a doctor was <scary_word pos="verb"
                    scale="0">examining</scary_word> his wound. Near the door a policeman stiffly
                kept guard. The hall was full of people; all the misery and vagabondism the streets
                contain at that hour was crowding in to see what had happened.</p>
            <p>Through the midst two men were being conveyed to the station-house; one, with his
                head <scary_word pos="adv" scale="1">dreadfully</scary_word> injured, on a
                stretcher, the other handcuffed, uttering <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2"
                    >frightful</scary_word> imprecations as he went.</p>
            <p>After a time the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">house</scary_word> was cleared of
                the rabble, the police took possession of it, and <character ref="mrTynan">Mr
                    Tynan</character> was sent for.</p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">What was that <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2"
                        >dreadful</scary_word> noise?</speech> asked Graham feebly, now seated on
                the floor, with his back resting against the wall.</p>
            <p><speech ref="mrTynan">I do not know. Was there a noise?</speech> said <character
                    ref="mrTynan">Mr Tynan</character>, humouring his fancy, as he thought.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="grahamCoulton">Yes, in the drawing-room, I think; the key is in my
                    pocket.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>Still humouring the wounded lad, <character ref="mrTynan">Mr Tynan</character> took
                the key and ran upstairs.</p>
            <p>When he unlocked the door, what a sight met his <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >eyes</scary_word>! The mirror had <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2"
                    >fallen</scary_word>—it was lying all over the floor <scary_word pos="verb"
                    scale="2">shivered</scary_word> into a thousand pieces; the console table had
                been borne <scary_word pos="adv" scale="1">down</scary_word> by its weight, and the
                marble slab was <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1">shattered</scary_word> as well. But
                this was not what chained his attention. Hundreds, thousands of gold pieces were
                scattered about, and an aperture behind the glass contained boxes filled with
                securities and deeds and bonds, the possession of which had cost his sister her
                life.</p>
            <p><speech ref="admiralCoulton">Well, <character ref="grahamCoulton">Graham</character>,
                    and what do you want?</speech> asked <character ref="admiralCoulton">Admiral
                    Coulton</character> that <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">evening</scary_word>
                as his eldest born appeared before him, looking somewhat <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="1">pale</scary_word> but otherwise unchanged.</p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">I want nothing,</speech> was the answer, <speech
                    ref="grahamCoulton">but to ask your forgiveness. <character ref="william"
                        >William</character> has told me all the story I never knew before; and, if
                    you let me, I will try to make it up to you for the <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="0">trouble</scary_word> you have had. I am provided for,</speech>
                went on the young fellow, with a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0"
                    >nervous</scary_word> laugh; <speech ref="grahamCoulton">I have made my fortune
                    since I left you, and another man's fortune as well.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="admiralCoulton">I think you are out of your senses,</speech> said the
                    <character ref="admiralCoulton">Admiral</character> shortly.</p>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">No, sir, I have found them,</speech> was the answer;
                    <speech ref="grahamCoulton">and I mean to <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0"
                        >strive</scary_word> and make a better thing of my life than I should ever
                    have done had I not gone to the Old House in Vauxhall Walk.</speech></p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="admiralCoulton">Vauxhall Walk! What is the lad talking about?</speech>
            </p>
            <plot point="resolve"/>
            <p><speech ref="grahamCoulton">I will tell you, sir, if I may sit <scary_word pos="adv"
                        scale="0">down</scary_word>,</speech> was <character ref="grahamCoulton"
                    >Graham Coulton</character>'s answer, and then he told his story.</p>
        </chapter>
    </body>
</story>
