<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../computational%20methods/ghostschema_update_3.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<story>
    <meta>
        <title>Walnut-Tree House</title>
        <author>Charlotte Riddell</author>
        <date>1882</date>
    </meta>
    <body>
        <plot point="intro"/>
        <chapter>
            <chapTitle>The New Owner</chapTitle>
            <p>Many years ago there stood at the corner of a street leading out of Upper Kennington
                Lane a great red brick <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word>, covering
                a goodly area of ground, and surrounded by gardens magnificent in their proportions
                when considered in relation to the populous neighbourhood mentioned.</p>
            <p>Originally a place of considerable pretention; a gentleman's seat in the country
                probably when Lambeth Marsh had not a shop in the whole of it; when Vauxhall Gardens
                were <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">still</scary_word> in nubilus; when no
                South-Western Railway was planned or thought of; when London was comparatively a
                    <scary_word pos="mod" scale="0">very</scary_word> small place, and its present
                suburbs were mere country villages—hamlets lying quite remote from the heart of the
                city.</p>
            <p>Once, the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word> in question had been
                surrounded by a small park, and at that time there were fish-ponds in the grounds,
                and quite a stretch of meadow-land within the walls. Bit by bit, however, the park
                had been cut up into building ground and let off on building leases; the meadows
                were covered with bricks and mortar, shops were run up where cows once chewed the
                cud, and the roar and rumble of London traffic sounded about the old <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word> and the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2"
                    >deserted</scary_word> garden, formerly quiet and <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="2">silent</scary_word> as though situated in some remote part of the
                country.</p>
            <p>Many a time in the course of the generations that had come and gone, been born and
                    <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2">buried</scary_word>, since the old <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word> was built, the freehold it covered
                changed hands. On most estates of this kind round London there generally is a
                residence, which passes like a horse from buyer to buyer. When it has served one
                man's need it is put up for sale and bid for by another. When rows and rows of
                houses, and line after line of streets, have obliterated all the familiar marks, it
                is impossible to cultivate a sentiment as regards property; and it is unlikely that
                the descendants of the first possessors of Walnut-Tree <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="1">House</scary_word> who had grown to be country folk and lived in great
                state, oblivious of business people, and entertaining a great contempt for trade,
                knew that in a <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i">very</scary_word> undesirable part of
                London there <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">still</scary_word> stood the residence
                where the first successful man of their family went home each day from his
                    counting-<scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word> over against St.
                Mildred's Church, in The Poultry.</p>
            <p>One <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i">very</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">wet</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">evening</scary_word>, in an autumn the leaves of
                which have been <scary_word pos="adj" scale="3">dead</scary_word> and gone this many
                a year, Walnut-Tree <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">House</scary_word>,
                    <scary_phrase>standing <scary_word pos="adj" scale="3">grim</scary_word> and
                        <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">lonely</scary_word> in the <scary_word
                        pos="adj" scale="2">mournful</scary_word>
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">twilight</scary_word></scary_phrase>, looked
                more than ordinarily <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">desolate</scary_word> and
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">deserted</scary_word>.</p>
            <p>There was not a sign of life about it; the <scary_phrase><scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="0">shutters</scary_word> were <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1"
                        >closed</scary_word></scary_phrase>—the <scary_phrase><scary_word pos="adj"
                        scale="1">rusty</scary_word> iron <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                        >gates</scary_word></scary_phrase> were fast <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                    >locked</scary_word>—the approach was <scary_phrase><scary_word pos="adj"
                        scale="3">choked</scary_word> up with <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                        >grass</scary_word> and <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >weeds</scary_word></scary_phrase>—through no chink did the light of a single
                candle flicker. <scary_phrase>For seven years it had been given over to <scary_word
                        pos="noun" scale="2">rats</scary_word> and <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                        >mice</scary_word> and <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                        >blackbeetles</scary_word></scary_phrase>; for seven years no one had been
                found to live in it; for seven years it had remained <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                    >empty</scary_word>, while its owner wore out existence in fits of <scary_word
                    pos="adj" scale="0">moody</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">dejection</scary_word> or of
                        <scary_phrase><scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">wild</scary_word>
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">frenzy</scary_word> in the <scary_word
                        pos="noun" scale="3">madhouse</scary_word></scary_phrase>
                <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">close</scary_word> at hand; and now that owner was
                        <scary_phrase><scary_word pos="adj" scale="3">dead</scary_word> and
                        <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2">buried</scary_word> and
                    forgotten</scary_phrase>, and the new owner was returning to take possession.
                This new owner had written to his lawyers, or rather he had written to the lawyers
                of his late relative, begging them to request the person in charge of the
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word> to have rooms prepared for
                his arrival; and, when the train drew into the station at Waterloo, he was met by
                    <character ref="clerk">one of the clerks</character> in Messrs Timpson and Co.'s
                office, who, picking out <character ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>,
                delivered to that gentleman a letter from the firm, and said he would wait and hear
                if there were any message in reply.</p>
            <plot point="protag"/>
            <p><character ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character> read the letter—looked at the
                blank flyleaf—and then, turning back to the first words, read what his solicitors
                had to say all through once again, this time aloud.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">The <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word>
                    has stood <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">empty</scary_word> for more than seven
                    years,</speech> he said, half addressing the <character ref="clerk"
                    >clerk</character> and half speaking to himself. <speech ref="clerk">Must be
                    damp and uninhabitable; there is no one living on the premises. Under these
                    circumstances we have been unable to comply with your directions, and can only
                    recommend you to go to an hotel till we are able personally to discuss future
                    arrangements.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">Humph,</speech> said the new owner, after he had
                finished. <speech ref="edgarStainton">I'll go and take a look at the place, anyhow.
                    Is it far from here, do you know?</speech> he asked, turning to the young man
                from Timpsons'.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="clerk">No, sir; not <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i">very</scary_word>
                    far.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">Can you spare time to come over there with me?</speech>
                continued <character ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>. The young man
                    <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0">believed</scary_word> that he could, adding,
                    <speech ref="clerk">If you want to go into the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                        >house</scary_word> we had better call for the key. It is at an estate
                    agent's in the Westminster Bridge Road.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">I cannot say I have any great passion for
                    hotels,</speech> remarked the new owner, as he took his seat in the cab.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="clerk">Indeed, sir?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">No; either they don't suit me, or I don't suit them. I
                    have led a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">wild</scary_word> sort of life: not
                    much civilisation in the bush, or at the goldfields, I can tell you. Rooms full
                    of furniture, houses where a fellow must keep to the one little corner he has
                    hired, seem to <scary_word pos="verb" scale="3">choke</scary_word> me. Then I
                    have not been well, and I can't stand noise and the trampling of feet. I had
                    enough of that on board ship; and I used to lie awake at <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="2">nights</scary_word> and think how pleasant it would be to have a
                    big <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word> all to myself, to do as
                    I liked in.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="clerk">Yes, sir,</speech> agreed the <character ref="clerk"
                    >clerk</character>.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">You see, I have been used to <scary_word pos="verb"
                        scale="1">roughing</scary_word> it, and I can get along <scary_word
                        pos="mod" scale="i">very</scary_word> well for a <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="1">night</scary_word> without servants.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="clerk">No doubt, sir.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">I suppose the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                        >house</scary_word> is in substantial repair—roof tight, and all that sort
                    of thing?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="clerk">I can't say, I am sure, sir.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">Well, if there is a dry corner where I can spread a
                    rug, I shall sleep there <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >tonight</scary_word>.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>The <character ref="clerk">clerk</character> coughed. He looked out of the
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">window</scary_word>, and then he looked at
                Messrs. Timpsons' client.</p>
            <p><speech ref="clerk">I do not think—</speech> he began, apologetically, and then
                stopped.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">You don't think what?</speech> asked the other.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="clerk">You'll excuse me, sir, but I don't think—I really do not think,
                    if I were you, I'd go to that <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                        >house</scary_word>
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">tonight</scary_word>.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">Why not?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="clerk">Well, it has not been slept in for nearly seven years, and it
                    must be blue <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">mouldy</scary_word> with damp; and
                    if you have been <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">ill</scary_word>, that is all
                    the more reason you should not run such a risk. And, besides—</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">Besides?</speech> suggested <character
                    ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>. <speech ref="edgarStainton">Out
                    with it! Like a postscript, no doubt, that 'besides' holds the marrow of the
                    argument.</speech></p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="clerk">The <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word> has
                    stood <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">empty</scary_word> for years, sir,
                    because—there is no use in making any <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                        >secret</scary_word> of it—the place has a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="3"
                        >bad</scary_word> name.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">What sort of a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="3"
                        >bad</scary_word> name—unhealthy?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="clerk">Oh, no!</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton"><scary_word pos="verb" scale="3"
                    >Haunted</scary_word>?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>The <character ref="clerk">clerk</character> inclined his head. <speech ref="clerk"
                    >You have hit it, sir,</speech> he said.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">And that is the reason no one has lived
                    there?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="clerk">We have been quite unable to let the <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="1">house</scary_word> on that account.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">The sooner it gets unhaunted, then, the
                    better,</speech> retorted <character ref="edgarStainton">Mr.
                    Stainton</character>. <speech ref="edgarStainton">I shall certainly stop there
                        <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">tonight</scary_word>. You are not disposed
                    to stay and keep me company, I suppose?</speech></p>
            <p>With a little gesture of dismay the <character ref="clerk">clerk</character> drew
                back. Certainly, this was one of the most unconventional of clients. The young man
                from Timpsons' did not at all know what to make of him.</p>
            <p><speech ref="clerk">A <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">rough</scary_word> sort of
                    fellow,</speech> he said afterwards, when describing the new owner; <speech
                    ref="clerk">boorish; never mixed with good society, that sort of
                    thing.</speech></p>
            <p>He did not in the least understand this rich man, who treated him as an equal, who
                objected to hotels, who didn't mind taking up his abode in a <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="1">house</scary_word> where not even a drunken charwoman could be induced
                to stop, and who calmly asked a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2"
                    >stranger</scary_word> on whom he had never set <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >eyes</scary_word> before—a <character ref="clerk">clerk</character> in the
                respectable office of Timpson and Co., a young fellow anxious to rise in the world,
                careful as to his associates, particular about the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >whiteness</scary_word> of his shirts and the sit of his collar and the cut of
                his coats—to <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">rough</scary_word> things with him in
                that <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">dreadful</scary_word> old <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="3">dungeon</scary_word>, where, perhaps, he might even be
                expected to light a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">fire</scary_word>.</p>
            <p><scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">Still</scary_word>, he did not wish to offend the new
                owner. Messrs. Timpson expected him to be a profitable client; and to that impartial
                firm the money of a boor would, he knew, seem as good as the money of a count.</p>
            <p><speech ref="clerk">I am <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i">very</scary_word>
                    sorry,</speech> he stammered; <speech ref="clerk">should only have felt too
                    much honoured; but the fact is—previous engagement—</speech></p>
            <p><character ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character> laughed.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">I understand,</speech> he said. <speech
                    ref="edgarStainton">Adventures are quite as much out of your line as
                        <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">ghosts</scary_word>. And now tell me about
                    this <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">apparition</scary_word>. Does the 'old
                    man' walk?</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="clerk">Not that I ever heard of,</speech> answered the other.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">Is it, then, the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2"
                        >miserable</scary_word> beggar who tried to do for himself?</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="clerk">It is not the late <character ref="edgarStainton">Mr.
                        Stainton</character>, I <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0"
                        >believe</scary_word>,</speech> said the young man, in tone which mildly
                suggested that reference to a client of Timpsons' as a <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="2">miserable</scary_word> beggar might be considered <scary_word
                    pos="adj" scale="3">bad</scary_word> taste.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">Then who on earth is it?</speech> persisted <character
                    ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="clerk">If you must know, sir, it is a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                        >child</scary_word>—a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">child</scary_word>
                    who has driven every tenant in succession out of the <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="1">house</scary_word>.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>The new owner burst into a hearty laugh—a laugh which gave <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="0">serious</scary_word> offence to Timpsons' <character ref="clerk"
                    >clerk</character>.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">That is too good a joke,</speech> said <character
                    ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>. <speech ref="edgarStainton">I do
                    not know when I heard anything so delicious.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="clerk">It is a fact, whether it be delicious or not,</speech> retorted
                the young man, driven out of all his former propriety of <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="0">voice</scary_word> and demeanour by the contemptuous ridicule this
                digger thought fit to cast on his story; <speech ref="clerk">and I, for one,
                    would not, after all I have heard about your <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                        >house</scary_word>, pass a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                        >night</scary_word> in it—no, not if anybody offered me fifty pounds
                        <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">down</scary_word>.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">Make your mind easy, my friend,</speech> said the new
                owner, <scary_word pos="adv" scale="1">quietly</scary_word>. <speech
                    ref="edgarStainton">I am not going to bid for your company. The <scary_word
                        pos="noun" scale="1">child</scary_word> and I can manage, I'll be bound, to
                    get on <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i">very</scary_word> comfortably by
                    ourselves.</speech></p>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
            <chapTitle>The Child</chapTitle>
            <p>It was later on in the same <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">evening</scary_word>;
                Mr. Stainton had an hour previously taken possession of Walnut-Tree <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="1">House</scary_word>, dismissed his cab, bidden Timpsons'
                    <character ref="clerk">clerk</character> good <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >evening</scary_word>, and, having ordered in wood and coals from the nearest
                greengrocer, besides various other necessary articles from various other tradesmen,
                he now stood by the front <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">gate</scary_word> waiting
                the coming of the goods purchased.</p>
            <p>As he waited, he looked up at the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                >house</scary_word>, which in the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                    >uncertain</scary_word> light of the street lamps appeared <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="2">gloomier</scary_word> and <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2"
                    >darker</scary_word> than had been the case even in the gathering <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="1">twilight</scary_word>.</p>
            <p>The long rows of <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">shuttered</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">windows</scary_word>, the <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="2">silent</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">solemnity</scary_word> of the great <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="2">trees</scary_word>, remnants of a once goodly avenue that
                had served to give its name to Walnut-Tree <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >House</scary_word>; the appalling <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2"
                    >silent</scary_word> of everything within the place, when contrasted with the
                noise of passing cabs and whistling street boys, and men trudging home with unfurled
                umbrellas and women scudding along with draggled petticoats, might well have
                impressed even an unimpressionable man, and <character ref="edgarStainton">Edgar
                    Stainton</character>, spite of his hard life and <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                    >rough</scary_word> exterior, was impressionable and imaginative.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">It has an 'uncanny' look, certainly,</speech> he
                considered; <speech ref="edgarStainton">but is not so cheerless for a <scary_word
                        pos="adj" scale="1">lonely</scary_word> man as the 'bush'; and though I am
                    not over-tired, I fancy I shall sleep more soundly in my new home than I did
                    many a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">night</scary_word> at the goldfields.
                    When once I can get a good <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">fire</scary_word> up
                    I shall be all right. Now, I wonder when those coals are coming!</speech></p>
            <p>As he turned once again towards the road, he beheld on its way the sack of fuel with
                which the nearest greengrocer said he thought he could—indeed, said he
                would—oblige him. A ton—half a ton—quarter of a ton, the greengrocer affirmed
                would be impossible until the next day; but a sack—yes—he would promise that.
                    <character ref="bill">Bill</character> should bring it round; and <character
                    ref="bill">Bill</character> was told to put his <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >burden</scary_word> on the truck, and twelve bundles of wood, <speech
                    ref="billsMaster">and we'll make up the rest to-morrow,</speech> added
                    <character ref="billsMaster">Bill's master</character>, with the <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="0">air</scary_word> of one who has conferred a favour.</p>
            <p>In the distance <character ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character> descried a
                    <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i">very</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">grimy</scary_word>
                <character ref="bill">Bill</character>, and a <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i"
                    >very</scary_word> small <character ref="boyBill">boy</character>, coming along
                with the truck leisurely, as though the load had been Herculean.</p>
            <p>Through the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">rain</scary_word> he watched the pair
                advancing and greeted <character ref="bill">Bill</character> with a glad <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="0">voice</scary_word> of welcome.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">So you've come at last; that's right. Better late than
                    never. Bring them this way. I'll have this small lot shot in the kitchen for the
                        <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">night</scary_word>.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="bill">Begging your pardon, sir,</speech> answered <character
                    ref="bill">Bill</character>, <speech ref="bill">I don't think you will—that is
                    to say, not by me. As I told our governor, I'll take 'em to the <scary_word
                        pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word> as you've sold 'em to the
                        <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word>, but I won't set a foot
                    inside it.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">Do you mean to say you are going to leave them out on
                    the pavement?</speech> asked Mr. Stainton.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="bill">Well, sir, I don't mind taking them to the front door if it'll
                    be a convenience.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">That will do. You are a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0"
                        >brave</scary_word> lot of people in these parts I must say.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="bill">As for that,</speech> retorted <character ref="bill"
                    >Bill</character>, with sack on back and head bent forward, <speech ref="bill"
                    >I dare say we're as <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">brave</scary_word> about
                    here as where you come from.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">It is not impossible,</speech> retorted <character
                    ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>; <speech ref="edgarStainton">there
                    are plenty of <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">cowards</scary_word> over there
                    too.</speech></p>
            <p>With a feint of being <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i">very</scary_word> much
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">afraid</scary_word>, <character ref="bill"
                    >Bill</character>, after he had shot his coals on the margin of the steps,
                retreated from the door, which stood partly open, and when the <character
                    ref="boyBill">boy</character> who brought up the wood was again out with the
                truck, said, putting his knuckles to his eyebrows:</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="boyBill">Beg pardon, sir, but I suppose you couldn't give us a drop of
                    beer? <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i">Very</scary_word>
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">wet</scary_word>
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">night</scary_word>, sir.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">No, I could not,</speech> answered <character
                    ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>, <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i"
                    >very</scary_word> decidedly. <speech ref="edgarStainton">I shall have to
                    shovel these coals into the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word>
                    myself; and, as for the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">night</scary_word>, it
                    is as <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">wet</scary_word> for me as it is for
                    you.</speech></p>
            <p>Nevertheless, as <character ref="bill">Bill</character> shuffled along the short
                drive—shuffling wearily—like a man who, having nearly finished one day's hard work,
                was looking forward to beginning another hard day in the morning, the new owner
                relented.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">Here,</speech> he said, picking out a sixpence to give
                him, <speech ref="edgarStainton">it isn't your fault, I suppose, that you
                        <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0">believe</scary_word> in old women's
                    tales.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="bill">Thank you kindly, sir,</speech>
                <character ref="bill">Bill</character> answered; <speech ref="bill">I am sure I am
                    extremely obliged; but if I was in your shoes I wouldn't stop in that
                        <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word>—you'll excuse me, sir,
                    meaning no offence—but I wouldn't; indeed I wouldn't.</speech></p>
            <p>It seems to have got a good name, at any rate, thought <character
                    ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>, while retracing his steps to the
                banned tenement. Let us see what effect a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >fire</scary_word> will have in routing the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2"
                    >shadows</scary_word>.</p>
            <p>He entered the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word>, and, striking a
                match, lighted some candles he had brought in with him from a neighbouring
                oil-shop.</p>
            <p>Years previously the gas company, <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">weary</scary_word>
                of receiving no profit from the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word>,
                had taken away their meter and cut off their connections. The water supply was in
                the same case, as <character ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>, going
                round the premises before it grew quite <scary_word pos="adj" scale="3"
                    >dark</scary_word>, had discovered.</p>
            <p>Of almost all small articles of furniture easily <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2"
                    >broken</scary_word> by careless tenants, easily removed by charwomen, the place
                was perfectly <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">bare</scary_word>; and as there were
                no portable candlesticks in which to place the lights the new tenant was forced to
                make his illumination by the help of some <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                    >dingy</scary_word> mirrors provided with sconces, and to seek such articles as
                he needed by the help of a guttering <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2"
                    >mould</scary_word> candle stuck in the neck of a <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="2">broken</scary_word> bottle. After an inspection of the ground-floor
                rooms he decided to take up his quarters for the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >night</scary_word> in one which had evidently served as a library.</p>
            <p>In the centre of the apartment there was the table covered with leather. Around the
                walls were bookcases, <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">still</scary_word> well filled
                with volumes, too <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">uninviting</scary_word> to borrow,
                too valueless in the opinion of the ignorant to <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1"
                    >steal</scary_word>. In one corner stood a bureau, where the man, who for so
                many years had been <scary_word pos="adj" scale="3">dead</scary_word> even while
                living, kept his letters and papers.</p>
            <p>The floor was <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">bare</scary_word>. Once a Turkey carpet
                had been spread over the centre of the polished oak boards, but it lay in its wonted
                place no longer; between the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">windows</scary_word>
                hung a convex mirror, in which the face of any human being looked <scary_word
                    pos="adj" scale="3">horrible</scary_word> and <scary_word pos="adj" scale="3"
                    >distorted</scary_word>; whilst over the mantle-shelf, indeed, forming a portion
                of it, was a long, narrow glass, bordered by a frame ornamented with a tracery of
                leaves and flowers. The ceiling was richly decorated, and, spite of the dust and
                dirt and neglect of years, all the appointments of the apartment he had selected
                gave <character ref="edgarStainton">Edgar Stainton</character> the impression that
                it was a good thing to be the owner of such a mansion, even though it did chance to
                be situated as much out of the way of fashionable London as the diggings whence he
                had come.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">And there is not a creature but myself left to enjoy it
                    all,</speech> he mused, as he sat looking into the blazing coals. <speech
                    ref="edgarStainton">My <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">poor</scary_word>
                    mother, how she would have rejoiced <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                        >tonight</scary_word>, had she lived to be the mistress of so large a place!
                    And my father, what a harbour this would have seemed after the <scary_word
                        pos="noun" scale="2">storms</scary_word> that buffeted him! Well, they are
                    better off, I know; and yet I cannot help thinking how <scary_word pos="adj"
                        scale="2">strange</scary_word> it all is—that I, who went away a mere
                    beggar, should come home rich, to be made richer, and yet stand so utterly
                        <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">alone</scary_word> that in the length and
                    breadth of England I have not a relative to welcome me or to say I wish you joy
                    of your inheritance.</speech></p>
            <plot point="haunting"/>
            <p>He had eaten his frugal supper, and now, pushing aside the table on which the remains
                of his repast were spread, he began walking <scary_word pos="adv" scale="1" synset="slowly.r.01"
                    >slowly</scary_word> up and <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0" synset="down.r.01">down</scary_word> the
                room, thinking over the past and forming plans for the future.</p>
            <p>As he was <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2" synset="immerse.v.03">buried</scary_word> in reflection, the
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1" synset="fire.n.04">fire</scary_word> began to <scary_word
                    pos="verb" scale="3" synset="die.v.10">die</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1" synset="down.r.05">down</scary_word> without his noticing the fact; but
                a sudden feeling of chilliness at length causing him <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1" synset="instinctively.r.01"
                    >instinctively</scary_word> to look towards the hearth, he threw some wood into
                the grate, and, while the flames went blazing up the wide chimney, piled on coals as
                though he desired to set the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1" synset="house.n.01">house</scary_word>
                alight.</p>
            <p>While he was so engaged there came a knock at the door of the room—a feeble,
                hesitating knock, which was <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1" synset="repeat.v.01">repeated</scary_word>
                more than once before it attracted <character ref="edgarStainton">Mr.
                    Stainton</character>'s attention.</p>
            <p>When it did, being <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">still</scary_word> busy with the
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1" synset="still.r.01">fire</scary_word>, and forgetting he was
                <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2" synset="alone.s.02">alone</scary_word> in the <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="1" synset="house.n.01">house</scary_word>, he called out, <speech ref="edgarStainton">Come
                    in.</speech></p>
            <p>Along the panels there <scary_word pos="verb" scale="3" synset="steal.v.02">stole</scary_word>
                <scary_phrase>a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2" synset="rustle.v.01">rustling</scary_word> sort of
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2" synset="touch.n.01">touch</scary_word></scary_phrase>, as if
                someone were feeling <scary_word pos="adv" scale="2" synset="uncertainly.r.02">uncertainly</scary_word> for
                the handle—a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2" synset="curious.s.01">curious</scary_word> noise, as of a
                weak hand <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2" synset="grope.v.01">fumbling</scary_word> about the door in
                the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="3" synset="darkness.n.02">dark</scary_word>; then, in a similar manner,
                the person seeking admittance tried to turn the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2" synset="lock.n.01"
                    >lock</scary_word>.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">Come in, can't you?</speech>
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1" synset="repeat.v.01">repeated</scary_word>
                <character ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>; but even as he spoke he
                remembered he was, or ought to be, the sole occupant of the mansion.</p>
            <p>He was not <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1" synset="alarmed.s.01">alarmed</scary_word>; he was too much
                accustomed to <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1" synset="solitude.n.01">solitude</scary_word> and danger for
                that; but he rose from his stooping position and <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1" synset="instinctively.r.01"
                    >instinctively</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1" synset="seize.v.01">seized</scary_word> his revolver, which he had
                chanced, while unpacking some of his effects, to place on the top of the bureau.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">Come in, whoever you are,</speech> he cried; but seeing
                the door remained <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">closed</scary_word>, though the
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3" synset="intruder.n.01">intruder</scary_word> was evidently making
                futile efforts to open it, he strode half-way across the room, and then stopped,
                amazed.</p>
            <p>For suddenly the door opened, and there entered, shyly and timidly, a little
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2" synset="child.n.01">child</scary_word>—a <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="2" synset="child.n.01">child</scary_word> with the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2" synset="sad.a.01"
                    >saddest</scary_word> face mortal ever beheld; a <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="2" synset="child.n.01">child</scary_word> with <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2" synset="pensive.s.02"
                    >wistful</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2" synset="eye.n.01">eyes</scary_word> and long, <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="2" synset="ill.r.01">ill</scary_word>-kept hair; a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2" synset="child.n.01"
                    >child</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2" synset="ill.r.01">poorly</scary_word> dressed, <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="2" synset="atrophied.a.01">wasted</scary_word> and <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2" synset="careworn.s.01"
                        >worn</scary_word>, and with the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2" synset="mournful.s.01"
                    >mournfullest</scary_word> expression on its countenance that face of a
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2" synset="child.n.01">child</scary_word> ever wore.</p>
            <p>What a hungry little beggar, thought <character ref="edgarStainton">Mr.
                    Stainton</character>. <speech ref="edgarStainton">Well, young one, and what do
                    you want here?</speech> he added, aloud.</p>
            <p>The<character ref="georgeStainton">boy</character>never answered, never took the
                slightest notice of his questioner, but simply walked <scary_word pos="adv"
                    scale="2" synset="slowly.r.01">slowly</scary_word> round the room, <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2" synset="peer.v.01"
                    >peering</scary_word> into all the corners, as if looking for something.
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1" synset="search.v.04">Searching</scary_word> the embrasures of the
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1" synset="window.n.01">windows</scary_word>, <scary_word pos="verb"
                    scale="1" synset="examine.v.02">examining</scary_word> the recesses beside the <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="1" synset="fireplace.n.01">fireplace</scary_word>, <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1" synset="hesitate.v.02"
                    >pausing</scary_word> on the hearth to glance under the library table, and
                finally, when the doorway was reached once more, turning to survey the contents of
                the apartment with an eager and yet <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2" synset="hopeless.a.01"
                    >hopeless</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1" synset="examination.n.01">scrutiny</scary_word>.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">What is it you want, my <character ref="georgeStainton"
                        >boy?</character></speech> asked <character ref="edgarStainton">Mr.
                    Stainton</character>, glancing as he spoke at the <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="2" synset="child.n.01">child</scary_word>'s <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1" synset="hapless.s.01">poor</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2" synset="thin.a.01">thin</scary_word> legs, and short, <scary_word
                    pos="adj" scale="1" synset="moth-eaten.s.01">shabby</scary_word> frock, and shoes wellnigh <scary_word
                        pos="adj" scale="2" synset="worn.a.01">worn</scary_word> out, and arms <scary_word pos="adj"
                            scale="2" synset="bare.s.01">bare</scary_word> and lean and unbeautiful. <speech ref="">Is it
                    anything I can get for you?</speech></p>
            <p>Not a word—not a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1" synset="whisper.n.01">whisper</scary_word>; only for
                reply a glance of the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1" synset="pensive.s.02">wistful</scary_word> brown
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2" synset="eye.n.01">eyes</scary_word>.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">Where do you come from, and who do you belong
                    to?</speech> persisted <character ref="edgarStainton">Mr.
                Stainton</character>.</p>
            <p>The <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2" synset="child.n.01">child</scary_word> turned <scary_word pos="adv"
                    scale="2" synset="slowly.r.01">slowly</scary_word> away.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">Come, you shall not get off so easily as you seem to
                    imagine,</speech> persisted the new owner, advancing towards his visitor.
                    <speech ref="edgarStainton">You have no business to be here at all; and before
                    you go you must tell me how you chance to be in this <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="1" synset="house.n.01">house</scary_word>, and what you expected to find in this
                    room.</speech></p>
            <p>He was <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1" synset="close.a.01">close</scary_word> to the doorway by this
                time, and the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2" synset="child.n.01">child</scary_word> stood on the
                threshold, with its back towards him.</p>
            <p><character ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character> could see every detail of the
                boy's attire—his little plaid frock, which he had <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0" synset="outgrow.v.01"
                    >outgrown</scary_word>, the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1" synset="hook.n.04">hooks</scary_word>
                which fastened it; the pinafore, <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2" synset="dirty.a.01">soiled</scary_word>
                and <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2" synset="rumple.v.03">crumpled</scary_word>, tied behind with strings
                <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2" synset="broken.a.01">broken</scary_word> and <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="2" synset="knotted.s.01">knotted</scary_word>; in one place the skirt had given from the body,
                and a piece of <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2" synset="flimsy.s.03">thin</scary_word>, <scary_word
                    pos="adj" scale="1" synset="inadequate.s.02">poor</scary_word> flannel showed that the <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="2" synset="child.n.01">child</scary_word>'s under habiliments matched in
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1" synset="shabbiness.n.01">shabbiness</scary_word> his exterior
                garments.</p>
            <p><scary_word pos="adj" scale="1" synset="hapless.s.01">Poor</scary_word> little chap, thought <character
                    ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>. <speech ref="edgarStainton">I
                    wonder if he would like something to eat. Are you hungry, my lad?</speech></p>
            <p>The <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1" synset="child.n.01">child</scary_word> turned and looked at him
                earnestly, but answered never a word.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">I wonder if he is dumb,</speech> marvelled <character
                    ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>; and, seeing he was moving away,
                put out a hand to detain him. But the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2" synset="child.n.01"
                    >child</scary_word> eluded his <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3" synset="touch.n.01"
                    >touch</scary_word>, and flitted out into the hall and up the wide staircase
                with swift, <scary_word pos="adj" scale="3" synset="noiseless.s.01">noiseless</scary_word> feet.</p>
            <p>Only waiting to snatch a candle from one of the sconces, <character
                    ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character> pursued as fast as he could
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1" synset="follow.v.01">follow</scary_word>.</p>
            <p>Up the easy steps he ran at the top of his speed; but, fast as he went, the
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2" synset="child.n.01">child</scary_word> went faster. Higher and
                higher he beheld the tiny creature mounting, then, <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0" synset="still.r.01"
                    >still</scary_word> keeping the same distance between them, it turned when it
                reached the top storey and trotted along a narrow corridor with rooms opening off to
                right and left. At the extreme end of this passage a door stood ajar. Through this
                the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2" synset="child.n.01">child</scary_word> passed, <character
                    ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>
                <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0" synset="still.r.01">still</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1" synset="follow.v.01">following</scary_word>.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">I have run you to earth at last,</speech> he said,
                entering and <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1" synset="close.v.01">closing</scary_word> the door. <speech
                    ref="edgarStainton">Why, where has the<character ref="georgeStainton"
                        >boy</character>gone?</speech> he added, holding the candle above his head
                and gazing round the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1" synset="begrimed.s.01">dingy</scary_word> garret in
                which he found himself.</p>
            <p>The room was quite <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2" synset="empty.a.01">empty</scary_word>. He <scary_word
                pos="verb" scale="1" synset="examine.v.02">examined</scary_word> it <scary_word pos="adv" scale="1" synset="close.r.02"
                    >closely</scary_word>, but could find no possible outlet save the door, and a
                skylight which had evidently not been opened for years.</p>
            <p>There was no furniture in the apartment, except a truckle bedstead, a rush-bottomed
                chair, and a rickety washstand. No wardrobe, or box or press where even a kitten
                might have lain concealed.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">It is <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i" synset="very.r.01">very</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2" synset="strange.a.01">strange</scary_word>,</speech>
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1" synset="mumble.v.01">muttered</scary_word>
                <character ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>, as he turned away baffled.
                <speech ref="edgarStainton"><scary_word pos="mod" scale="i" synset="very.r.01">very</scary_word>
                        <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2" synset="strange.a.01">strange</scary_word>!</speech> he <scary_word
                            pos="verb" scale="1" synset="repeat.v.01">repeated</scary_word>, while he walked along the corridor.
                    <speech ref="edgarStainton">I don't understand it at all,</speech> he decided,
                proceeding <scary_word pos="adv" scale="1" synset="slowly.r.01">slowly</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0" synset="down.r.01">down</scary_word> the topmost flight of stairs; but
                then all at once he stopped.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">IT IS THE <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3" synset="child.n.01"
                        >CHILD</scary_word>!</speech> he exclaimed aloud, and the sound of his own
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1" synset="voice.n.01">voice</scary_word> woke
                <scary_phrase><scary_word pos="adj" scale="1" synset="strange.a.01">strange</scary_word>
                    <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2" synset="echo.n.01">echoes</scary_word> through the <scary_word
                        pos="noun" scale="2" synset="silence.n.01">silence</scary_word> of that <scary_word pos="adj"
                            scale="2" synset="desolate.s.02">desolate</scary_word>
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1" synset="house.n.01">house</scary_word></scary_phrase>. <speech
                    ref="edgarStainton">IT IS THE <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3" synset="child.n.01"
                        >CHILD</scary_word>!</speech> And he descended the principal staircase
                    <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i" synset="very.r.01">very</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="adv" scale="2" synset="slowly.r.01">slowly</scary_word>, with bowed head, and his
                <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2" synset="grave.s.01">grave</scary_word>, thoughtful face <scary_word
                    pos="adj" scale="2" synset="grave.s.01">graver</scary_word> and more thoughtful than ever.</p>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
            <chapTitle>Seeking for Information</chapTitle>
            <p>It was enough to make any man look <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2" synset="grave.s.01"
                >grave</scary_word>; and as time went on the new owner of Walnut-Tree <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="1" synset="house.n.01">House</scary_word> found himself pondering continually as
                to what the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2" synset="mystery.n.01">mystery</scary_word> could be which
                attached to the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2" synset="child.n.01">child</scary_word> he had found in
                possession of his property, and who had already driven tenant after tenant out of
                the premises. Inclined at first to regard the <character ref="clerk"
                    >clerk</character>'s story as a joke, and his own experience on the <scary_word
                        pos="noun" scale="1" synset="night.n.01">night</scary_word> of his arrival a delusion, it was
                impossible for him to continue incredulous when he found, even in broad daylight,
                that <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2" synset="awful.s.02">terrible</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2" synset="child.n.01">child</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="3" synset="steal.v.02">stealing</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0" synset="down.r.01">down</scary_word> the staircase and entering the
                rooms, looking—looking, for something it never found.</p>
            <p>Never after the first <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3" synset="horror.n.01">horror</scary_word> was over
                did <character ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character> think of leaving the
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1" synset="house.n.01">house</scary_word> in consequence of that
                haunting presence which had kept the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1" synset="house.n.01"
                    >house</scary_word> tenantless. It would have been worse than useless, he felt.
                With the ocean stretching between, his spirit would <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0" synset="still.r.01"
                    >still</scary_word> be in the old mansion at Lambeth—his mental vision would
                always be watching the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1" synset="child.n.01">child</scary_word> engaged
                in the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2" synset="aweary.s.01">weary</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2" synset="search.n.01">search</scary_word> to which there seemed no
                end—that never appeared to produce any result.</p>
            <p>At bed and at board he had company, or the expectation of it. No apartment in the
                building was secure from intrusion. It did not matter where he lay; it did not
                matter where he ate; between sleeping and waking, between breakfast and dinner,
                whenever the notion <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1">seized</scary_word> it, the
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2" synset="child.n.01">child</scary_word> came gliding in, looking,
                looking, looking, and never finding; not lingering longer than was necessary to be
                certain the object of its <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2" synset="search.n.01">search</scary_word> was
                absent, but <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2" synset="wander.v.03">wandering</scary_word> hither and
                thither, from garret to kitchen, from parlour to bed-chamber, in that quest which
                    <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0" synset="still.r.01">still</scary_word> seemed fresh as when first
                begun.</p>
            <p><character ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character> went to his solicitors as the
                most likely persons from whom to obtain information on the subject, and plunged at
                once into the matter.</p>
            <plot point="history"/>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">Who is the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                        >child</scary_word> supposed to be, <character ref="mrTimpson">Mr.
                        Timpson</character>?</speech> he asked, making no <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="2">secret</scary_word> that he had seen it.</p>
            <p><speech ref="mrTimpson">Well, that is really <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i"
                        >very</scary_word> difficult to say,</speech> answered <character
                    ref="mrTimpson">Mr. Timpson</character>.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">There was a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                        >child</scary_word> once, I suppose—a real <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                        >child</scary_word>—<scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">flesh</scary_word> and
                        <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">blood</scary_word>?</speech>
            </p>
            <p><character ref="mrTimpson">Mr. Timpson</character> took off his spectacles and wiped
                them.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrTimpson">There were two; yes, certainly, in the time of Mr.
                        <character ref="felixStainton">Felix Stainton</character>—a<character
                        ref="georgeStainton">boy</character>and a girl.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">In that <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                        >house</scary_word>?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrTimpson">In that <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >house</scary_word>. They survived him.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">And what became of them?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrTimpson">The girl was adopted by a relation of her father's, and
                        the—boy—<scary_word pos="verb" scale="3">died</scary_word>.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">Oh the<character ref="georgeStainton"
                        >boy</character><scary_word pos="verb" scale="3">died</scary_word>, did he?
                    Do you happen to know what he <scary_word pos="verb" scale="3">died</scary_word>
                    of?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrTimpson">No; I really do not. There was nothing <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="2">wrong</scary_word> about the affair, however, if that is what you
                    are thinking of. There never was a hint of that sort.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><character ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character> sat <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="1">silent</scary_word> for a minute; then he said:</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton"><character ref="mrTimpson">Mr. Timpson</character>, I
                    can't shake off the idea that somehow there has been <scary_word pos="adj"
                        scale="2">foul</scary_word> play with regard to those children. Who were
                    they?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrTimpson"><character ref="felixStainton">Felix Stainton</character>'s
                    grandchildren. His daughter made a low marriage, and he cast her adrift. After
                    her <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">death</scary_word> the two children were
                    received at Walnut-Tree <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">House</scary_word> on
                    sufferance—fed and clothed, I <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0"
                        >believe</scary_word>, that was all; and when the old man <scary_word
                        pos="verb" scale="3">died</scary_word> the heir-at-law permitted them to
                    remain.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton"><character ref="alfredStainton">Alfred</character>
                    Stainton?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrTimpson">Yes; the unhappy man who became insane. His uncle
                        <scary_word pos="verb" scale="3">died</scary_word> intestate, and he
                    consequently succeeded to everything but the personalty, which was <scary_word
                        pos="mod" scale="i">very</scary_word> small, and of which these children had
                    a share.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">There was never any suspicion you say, of <scary_word
                        pos="adj" scale="2">foul</scary_word> play on the part of the late
                    owner?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrTimpson">Dear, dear! No; quite the contrary.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">Then can you throw the least light on the <scary_word
                        pos="noun" scale="2">mystery</scary_word>?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrTimpson">Not the least; I wish I could.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>For all that, <character ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character> carried away an
                impression <character ref="mrTimpson">Mr. Timpson</character> knew more of the
                matter than he cared to tell; and was confirmed in this opinion by a chance remark
                from <character ref="mrTimpson">Mr. Timpson</character>'s partner, whom he met in
                the street almost immediately after.</p>
            <p><speech ref="co.">Why can't you let the matter rest, <character ref="edgarStainton"
                        >Mr. Stainton</character>?</speech> asked the <character ref="co."
                    >Co.</character> with some irritation of manner when he heard the object of
                their client's visit. <speech ref="co.">What is the use of troubling your head
                    about a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">child</scary_word> who has been lying
                    in Lambeth Churchyard these dozen years? Take my advice, have the <scary_word
                        pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word> pulled <scary_word pos="adv"
                        scale="0">down</scary_word> and let or sell the ground for building. You
                    ought to get a pot of money for it in that neighbourhood. If there were a
                        <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">wrong</scary_word> done it is too late to set it
                    right now.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">What <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">wrong</scary_word>
                    do you refer to?</speech> asked <character ref="edgarStainton">Mr.
                    Stainton</character> eagerly, thinking he had caught Timpson's partner napping.
                But that gentleman was too sharp for him.</p>
            <p><speech ref="co.">I remarked if there were a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2"
                        >wrong</scary_word> done—not that there had been one,</speech> he answered;
                and then, without a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">pause</scary_word>, added,
                    <speech ref="co.">We shall hope to hear from you that you have decided to
                        <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1">follow</scary_word> our
                advice.</speech></p>
            <p>But <character ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0">shook</scary_word> his head.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">I will not pull <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0"
                        >down</scary_word> the old <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                        >house</scary_word> just yet, </speech>he said, and walked <scary_word
                    pos="adv" scale="0">slowly</scary_word> away.</p>
            <p>There is a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">mystery</scary_word> behind it all, he
                considered. I must learn more about these children. Perhaps some of the local
                tradespeople may recollect them.</p>
            <p>But the local tradespeople for the most part were newcomers—or else had not supplied
                the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word>.</p>
            <p><speech ref="butcher">So far as ever I could understand,</speech> said one family
                    <character ref="butcher">butcher</character>, <scary_word pos="adv" scale="1"
                    >irascibly</scary_word> sharpening his knife as he spoke, <speech ref="butcher"
                    >there was not much to supply. That custom was not worth speaking of. I hadn't
                    it, so what I am saying is not said on my own account. A scrag end of neck of
                    mutton—a bit of gravy beef—two pennyworth of sheep's liver—that was the sort of
                    thing. Misers, sir, misers; the old gentleman <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                        >bad</scary_word>, and the nephew worse. A <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                        >bad</scary_word> business, first and last. But what else could be expected?
                    When people as can afford to live on the fat of the land never have a sirloin
                    inside their doors, why, worse must come of it. No, sir, I never set <scary_word
                        pos="noun" scale="0">eyes</scary_word> on the children to my knowledge; I
                    only knew there were children by hearing one of them was <scary_word pos="adj"
                        scale="2">dead</scary_word>, and that it was the <scary_word pos="adj"
                        scale="1">poorest</scary_word> funeral ever crossed a decent
                    threshold.</speech></p>
            <p><scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">poor</scary_word> little chap, thought <character
                    ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>, looking straight out into the
                street for a moment; then added, <speech ref="edgarStainton">lest the family
                    misfortunes should descend to me, you had better send round a joint to
                    Walnut-Tree <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">House</scary_word>.</speech></p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="butcher">Lor', sir, are you the gentleman as is living there? I beg
                    your pardon, I am sure, but I have been so bothered with questions in regard of
                    that <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word> and those children that
                    I forget my manners when I talk about them. A joint, sir—what would you please
                    to have?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>The new owner told him; and while he counted out the money to pay for it <character
                    ref="butcher">Mr. Parker</character> remarked:</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="butcher">There is only one person I can think of sir, likely to be
                    able to give any information about the matter.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">And that is?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="butcher">Mr. <character ref="mrHennings">Hennings</character>, at the
                    ‘Pedlar's Dog.’ He had some aquaintance with the old lady as was housekeeper
                    both to Mr. <character ref="felixStainton">Felix Stainton</character> and the
                    gentleman that went out of his mind.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><scary_word pos="verb" scale="0">following</scary_word> the advice, the new owner
                repaired to the ‘Pedlar's Dog,’ where (having on his first arrival at Walnut-Tree
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">House</scary_word> ordered some creature
                comforts from that well-known public) he experienced a better reception than had
                been accorded to him by <character ref="butcher">Mr. Parker</character>.</p>
            <p><speech ref="mrHennings">Do I know Walnut-Tree <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                        >House</scary_word>, sir?</speech> said Mr. <character ref="mrHennings"
                    >Hennings</character>, <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0">repeating</scary_word>
                his visitor's question. <speech ref="mrHennings">Well, yes, rather. Why, you might
                    as well ask me, do I know the ‘Pedlar's Dog.’ As<character ref="georgeStainton"
                        >boy</character>and man I can remember the old <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="1">house</scary_word> for <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0"
                        >close</scary_word> on five-and-fifty years. I remember Mr. <character
                        ref="georgeStainton">George</character> Stainton; he used to wear a
                    skull-cap and knee-breeches. There was an orchard then where Stainton Street is
                    now, and his whole time was taken up in keeping the boys out of it. Many a time
                    I have run from him.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">Did you ever see anything of the<character
                        ref="georgeStainton">boy</character>and girl who were there, after Mr.
                        <character ref="alfredStainton">Alfred</character> succeeded to the
                        property—<character ref="felixStainton">Felix Stainton</character>'s
                    grandchildren, I mean?</speech> asked the new owner, when a <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="0">pause</scary_word> in <character ref="mrHennings">Mr.
                    Henning's</character> reminiscences enabled him to take his part in the
                conversation.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrHennings">Well, sir, I may have seen the girl, but I can't bring it
                    to my recollection; the<character ref="georgeStainton">boy</character>I do
                    remember, however. He came over here two or three times with Mrs. <character
                        ref="mrsToplis">Toplis</character>, who kept <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="1">house</scary_word> for both Mr. Staintons, and I took notice of
                    him, both because he looked so peaky and old-fashioned, and also on account of
                    the talk about him.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">There was talk about him, then?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrHennings">Bless you, yes, sir; as much talk while he was living as
                    since he <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2">died</scary_word>. Everybody thought
                    he ought to have been the heir.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">Why?</speech> enquired the new owner.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrHennings">Because there was a will made leaving the place to
                    him.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>Here was information. <character ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>'s heart
                seemed to stand <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0">still</scary_word> for a second and
                then leap on with excitement.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">Who made the will?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrHennings">The grandfather, <character ref="felixStainton">Felix
                        Stainton</character>, to be sure; who else should make it?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">I did not mean that. Was it not drawn out by a
                    solicitor?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrHennings">Oh! Yes—now I understand you, sir. The will was drawn
                    right enough by Mr. <character ref="mrQuinance">Quinance</character>, in the
                    Lambeth Road, a <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i">very</scary_word> clever
                    lawyer.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">Not by Timpson, then? How was that?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrHennings">The old man took the notion of making it late one
                        <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">night</scary_word>, and so Mrs. <character
                        ref="mrsToplis">Toplis</character> sent to the nearest lawyer she knew
                    of.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">Yes; and then?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrHennings">Well, the will was made and signed and witnessed, and
                    everything regular; and from that day to this no one knows what has become of
                    it.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">How <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i">very</scary_word>
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">strange</scary_word>.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrHennings">Yes, sir, it is more than <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                        >strange</scary_word>—unaccountable. At first Mr. <character
                        ref="mrQuinance">Quinance</character> was suspected of having given it up to
                    Mr. <character ref="alfredStainton">Alfred</character>; but Mrs. <character
                        ref="mrsToplis">Toplis</character> and <character ref="mrQuinance"
                        >Quinance</character>'s <character ref="clerk">clerk</character>—he has
                    succeeded to the business now—say that old Felix insisted upon keeping it
                    himself. So, whether he <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1">destroyed</scary_word>
                    it or the nephew got hold of it, Heaven only knows; for no man living does, I
                    think.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">And the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                        >child</scary_word>—the <character ref="georgeStainton">boy,</character> I
                    mean?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrHennings">If you want to hear all about him, sir, Mrs. <character
                        ref="mrsToplis">Toplis</character> is the one to tell you. If you have a
                    mind to give a shilling to a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">poor</scary_word>
                    old lady who always did try to keep herself respectable, and who, I will say,
                    paid her way honourable as long as she had a sixpence to pay it honourable with,
                    you cannot do better than go and see Mrs. <character ref="mrsToplis"
                        >Toplis</character>, who will talk to you for hours about the time she lived
                    at Walnut-Tree <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">House</scary_word>.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>And with this delicate hint that his minutes were more valuable than the hours of
                Mrs. <character ref="mrsToplis">Toplis</character>, Mr. <character ref="mrHennings"
                    >Hennings</character> would have <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0"
                    >closed</scary_word> the interview, but that his visitor asked where he should
                be able to find the housekeeper.</p>
            <p><speech ref="mrHennings">A thousand pardons!</speech> he answered, with an
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">air</scary_word>; <speech ref="mrHennings"
                    >forgetting the <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i">very</scary_word> cream and
                    marrow of it, wasn't I? Mrs. <character ref="mrsToplis">Toplis</character>, sir,
                    is to be found in Lambeth Workhouse—and a pity, too.</speech></p>
            <p><character ref="edgarStainton">Edgar Stainton</character> turned away, heartsick. Was
                this all wealth had done for his people and those connected with them?</p>
            <p>No man seemed to care to <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1">waste</scary_word> a moment
                in speaking about their affairs; no one had a good word for or kindly memory of
                them. The <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">poorest</scary_word> creature he met in
                the streets might have been of more use in the world then they. The <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word> they had lived in mentioned as if a
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">curse</scary_word> rested on the place;
                themselves only recollected as leaving everything undone which it befitted their
                station to do. An old servant allowed to end her days in the workhouse!</p>
            <p>Heaven helping me, he thought, I will not so misuse the wealth which has been
                given me.</p>
            <p>The slight put upon his family tortured and made him wince, and the face of the
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="3">dead</scary_word><character ref="georgeStainton"
                    >boy</character>who ought to have been the heir seemed, as he hurried along the
                streets, to pursue and look on him with a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                    >wistful</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">reproach</scary_word>.</p>
            <plot point="resolve"/>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">If I cannot lay that <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                        >child</scary_word> I shall go <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2"
                        >mad</scary_word>,</speech> he said, almost audibly, <speech
                    ref="edgarStainton">as <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">mad</scary_word>,
                    perhaps, as <character ref="alfredStainton">Alfred</character>
                    Stainton.</speech> And then a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2"
                    >terrible</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">fear</scary_word> took possession of him. The
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">horror</scary_word> of that which is worse than
                any <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">death</scary_word> made for the moment this
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">brave</scary_word>, bold man more timid than a
                woman.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">God preserve my senses,</speech> he prayed, and then,
                determinedly putting that <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">phantom</scary_word>
                behind him, he went on to the Workhouse.</p>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
            <chapTitle>Brother and Sister</chapTitle>
            <p><character ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character> had expected to find Mrs.
                    <character ref="mrsToplis">Toplis</character> a decrepit crone, bowed with age
                and racked with rheumatism, and it was therefore like a gleam of sunshine streaming
                across his path to behold a woman, elderly, certainly, but carrying her years with
                ease, ruddy cheeked, clear eyed, upright as a dart, who welcomed him with respectful
                enthusiasm.</p>
            <p><speech ref="mrsToplis">And so you are Mr. Edgar, the son of the dear old
                    Captain,</speech> she said, after the first greetings and explanations were
                over, after she had wiped her <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">eyes</scary_word> and
                uttered many ejaculations of astonishment and expressions of delight. <speech
                    ref="mrsToplis">Eh! I remember him coming to the <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="1">house</scary_word> just after he was married, and telling me about
                    the sweet lady his wife. I never heard a gentleman so proud; he never seemed
                    tired of saying the words, 'My wife'.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">She was a sweet lady,</speech> answered the new
                owner.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrsToplis">And so the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                        >house</scary_word> has come to you, sir? Well, I wish you joy. I hope you
                    may have peace, and health, and happiness, and prosperity in it. And I don't see
                    why you should not—no, indeed, sir.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><character ref="edgarStainton">Edgar Stainton</character> sat <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="0">silent</scary_word> for a minute, thinking how he should best approach
                his subject.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">Mrs. <character ref="mrsToplis"
                    >Toplis</character>,</speech> he began at last, plunging into the <scary_word
                    pos="mod" scale="i">very</scary_word> middle of the difficulty, <speech
                    ref="edgarStainton">I want you to tell me about it. I have come here on purpose
                    to ask you what it all means.</speech></p>
            <p>The old woman covered her face with her hands, and he could see that she <scary_word
                    pos="verb" scale="2">trembled</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">violently</scary_word>.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">You need not be <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2"
                        >afraid</scary_word> to speak openly to me,</speech> he went on. <speech
                    ref="edgarStainton">I am quite satisfied there was some great <scary_word
                        pos="noun" scale="2">wrong</scary_word> done in the <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="1">house</scary_word>, and I want to put it right, if it lies in my
                    power to do so. I am a rich man. I was rich when the news of this inheritance
                    reached me, and I would gladly give up the property to-morrow if I could only
                    undo whatever may have been done amiss.</speech></p>
            <p>Mrs. <character ref="mrsToplis">Toplis</character>
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0">shook</scary_word> her head.</p>
            <p><speech ref="mrsToplis">Ah, sir; you can't do that,</speech> she said. <speech
                    ref="mrsToplis">Money can't bring back the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2"
                        >dead</scary_word> to life; and, if it could, I doubt if even you could
                    prove as good a friend to the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">poor</scary_word>
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">child</scary_word> sleeping in the churchyard
                    yonder as his Maker did when He took him out of this <scary_word pos="adj"
                        scale="1">troublesome</scary_word> world. It was just soul rending to see
                    the <character ref="georgeStainton">boy</character>the last few months of his
                    life. I can't bear to think of it, sir! Often at <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="1">night</scary_word> I wake in a fright, fancying I <scary_word
                        pos="adv" scale="0">still</scary_word> hear the patter, patter of his
                        <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">poor</scary_word> little feet upon the
                    stair.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">Do you know, it is a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                        >curious</scary_word> thing, but he doesn't frighten me,</speech> said
                    <character ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>; <speech
                    ref="edgarStainton">that is when I am in the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                        >house</scary_word>; although when I am away from it the recollection seems
                    to dog every step I take.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="mrsToplis">What?</speech> cried Mrs. <character ref="mrsToplis"
                    >Toplis</character>. <speech ref="mrsToplis">Have you, then, seen him too?
                    There what am I talking about? I hope, sir, you will forgive my
                    foolishness.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">I see him constantly,</speech> was the calm reply.</p>
            <p><speech ref="mrsToplis">I wonder what it means!—I wonder what it can mean!</speech>
                exclaimed the housekeeper, wringing her hands in dire perplexity and dismay.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">I do not know,</speech> answered the new owner,
                philosophically; <speech ref="edgarStainton">but I want you to help me to find out.
                    I suppose you remember the children coming there at first?</speech></p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrsToplis">Well, sir—well, they were <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                        >poor</scary_word> Miss <character ref="maryFenton">Mary</character>'s son
                    and daughter. She ran away, you know, with a Mr. Fenton—made a <scary_word
                        pos="mod" scale="i">very</scary_word>
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">poor</scary_word> match; but I <scary_word
                        pos="verb" scale="0">believe</scary_word> he was kind to her. When they were
                    brought to us, a <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2">shivering</scary_word> little
                    pair, my master was for sending them here. Ay, and he would have done it, too,
                    if somebody had not said he could be made to pay for their keep. You never saw
                    brother and sister so fond of one another—never. They were twins. But, Lor'! the
                        <character ref="georgeStainton">boy</character>was more like a father to the
                    little girl than aught else. He'd have kept an apple a month rather than eat it
                    unless she had half; and the same with e<scary_word pos="mod" scale="i"
                        >very</scary_word>thing. I think it was seeing that—watching the love they
                    had, he for her and she for him, coming upon them unsuspected, with their little
                    arms round one another's necks, made the old gentleman alter his mind about
                    leaving the place to Mr. <character ref="alfredStainton">Alfred</character>; for
                    he said to me, one day, thoughtful like, pointing to them, 'Wonderful fond,
                        <character ref="mrsToplis">Toplis</character>!' and I answered, 'Yes, sir;
                    for all the world like the Babes in the Wood;' not thinking of how <scary_word
                        pos="adj" scale="1">lonely</scary_word> that meant—</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrsToplis">Shortly afterwards he took to his bed; and while he was
                    lying there, no doubt, better thoughts came to him, for he used to talk about
                    his wife and Miss <character ref="maryFenton">Mary</character>, and the Captain,
                    your father, sir, and ask if the children were gone to bed, and such like—things
                    he never used to mention before.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrsToplis">So when he made the will Mr. <character ref="mrQuinance"
                        >Quinance</character> drew out I was not surprised—no, not a bit. Though
                    before that time he always spoke of Mr. <character ref="alfredStainton"
                        >Alfred</character> as his heir, and treated him as such.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">That will never was found,</speech> suggested
                    <character ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>, anxious to get at
                another portion of the narrative.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrsToplis">Never, sir; we hunted for it high and low. Perhaps I
                        <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2">wronged</scary_word> him, but I always
                    thought Mr. <character ref="alfredStainton">Alfred</character> knew what became
                    of it. After the old gentleman's <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2"
                        >death</scary_word> the children were treated shameful—shameful. I don't
                    mean beaten, or that like; but <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2"
                        >half-starved</scary_word> and <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2"
                        >neglected</scary_word>. He would not buy them proper clothes, and he would
                    not suffer them to wear decent things if anybody else bought them. It was just
                    the same with their food. I durs'n't give them even a bit of bread and butter
                    unless it was on the sly; and, indeed, there was not much to give in that
                        <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">house</scary_word>. He turned regular
                    miser. Hoarding came into the family with Mrs. Lancelot Stainton, Mr. <character
                        ref="alfredStainton">Alfred</character>'s great grandmother, and they went
                    on from <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">bad</scary_word> to worse, each one
                        <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">closer</scary_word> and nearer than the
                    last, begging your pardon for saying so, sir; but it is the truth.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">I <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2">fear</scary_word> so,
                    Mrs. <character ref="mrsToplis">Toplis</character>,</speech> agreed the man,
                who certainly was neither <scary_word pos="adv" scale="1">close</scary_word> nor
                near.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrsToplis">Well, sir, at last, when the little girl was about six
                    years old, she fell <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">sick</scary_word>, and we
                    didn't think she would get over the illness. While she was about at her
                        <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">worst</scary_word>, Mrs. <character
                        ref="mayStainton">May</character>, her father's sister, chanced to be
                    stopping up in London, and, as Mr. <character ref="alfredStainton"
                        >Alfred</character> refused to let a doctor inside his doors, she made no
                    more ado but wrapped the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">child</scary_word> up
                    in blankets, sent for a cab, and carried her off to her own lodgings. Mr.
                        <character ref="alfredStainton">Alfred</character> made no objection to
                    that. All he said as she went through the hall was:</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrsToplis">'If you take her now, remember, you must keep
                    her.'</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrsToplis">'<scary_word pos="mod" scale="i">very</scary_word> well,'
                    she replied, 'I will keep her.'</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">And the <character ref="georgeStainton">boy?</character>
                    the <character ref="georgeStainton">boy?</character></speech> cried <character
                    ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>, in an <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="2">agony</scary_word> of impatience.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrsToplis">I am coming to him, sir, if you please. He just dwindled
                    away after his sister and he were parted, and <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2"
                        >died</scary_word> in December, as she was taken away in the July.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">What did he <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2"
                        >die</scary_word> of?</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrsToplis">A <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">broken</scary_word>
                    heart, sir. It seems a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">queer</scary_word> thing
                    to say about a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">child</scary_word>; but if ever
                    a heart was <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">broken</scary_word> his was. At
                    first he was always <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2">wandering</scary_word>
                    about the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">house</scary_word> looking for her,
                    but towards the end he used to go up to his room and stay there all by himself.
                    At last I wrote to Mrs. <character ref="mayStainton">May</character>, but she
                    was <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">ill</scary_word> when the letter got to her,
                    and when she did come up he was <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2"
                        >dead</scary_word>. My word, she talked to Mr. <character
                        ref="alfredStainton">Alfred</character>! I never heard any one person say so
                    much to another. She declared he had first cheated the<character
                        ref="georgeStainton">boy</character>of his inheritance, and then
                            <scary_phrase><scary_word pos="verb" scale="3">starved </scary_word>him
                        to <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">death</scary_word></scary_phrase>; but
                    that was not true, the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">child</scary_word>
                    <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2">broke</scary_word> his heart fretting after his
                    sister.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">Yes; and when he was <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2"
                        >dead</scary_word>—</speech>
            </p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrsToplis">Sir, I don't like to speak of it, but as true as I am
                    sitting here, the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">night</scary_word> he was put
                    in his coffin he came pattering <scary_word pos="adv" scale="2"
                        >down</scary_word> just as usual, looking, looking for his sister. I went
                    straight upstairs, and if I had not seen the little <scary_word pos="adj"
                        scale="2">wasted</scary_word> body lying there <scary_word pos="adj"
                        scale="3">still</scary_word> and quiet, I must have thought he had come back
                    to life. We were never without him afterwards, never; that, and nothing else,
                    drove Mr. <character ref="alfredStainton">Alfred</character>
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="3">mad</scary_word>. He used to think he was
                    fighting the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">child</scary_word> and <scary_word
                        pos="verb" scale="3">killing</scary_word> it. When the <scary_word pos="adj"
                        scale="3">worst</scary_word> fits were on him he tried to trample it under
                    foot or <scary_word pos="verb" scale="3">crush</scary_word> it up in a corner,
                    and then he would sob and <scary_word pos="verb" scale="3">cry</scary_word>, and
                    pray for it to be taken away. I have heard he recovered a little before he
                        <scary_word pos="verb" scale="3">died</scary_word>, and said his uncle told
                    him there was a will leaving all to the <character ref="georgeStainton"
                        >boy,</character> but he never saw such a paper. Perhaps it was all talk,
                    though, or that he was <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0">still</scary_word>
                    raving?</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">You are quite positive there was no <scary_word
                        pos="adj" scale="2">foul</scary_word> play as regards the <scary_word
                        pos="noun" scale="1">child</scary_word>?</speech> asked <character
                    ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>, sticking to that question
                pertinaciously.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mrsToplis">Certain, sir; I don't say but Mr. <character
                        ref="alfredStainton">Alfred</character> wished him <scary_word pos="adj"
                        scale="2">dead</scary_word>. That is not <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2"
                        >murder</scary_word>, though.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">I am not clear about that,</speech> answered <character
                    ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>.</p>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
            <chapTitle>The Next Afternoon</chapTitle>
            <p><character ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character> was trying to work off some
                portion of his perplexities by pruning the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2"
                    >grimy</scary_word> evergreens in front of Walnut-Tree <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="1">House</scary_word>, and chopping away at the undergrowth of
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">weeds</scary_word> and couch <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="2">grass</scary_word> which had in the course of years matted
                together beneath the shrubs, when his attention was attracted to two ladies who
                stood outside the great iron <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">gate</scary_word>
                looking up at the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">house</scary_word>.</p>
            <p><speech ref="mayStainton">It seems to be occupied now,</speech> remarked the elder,
                turning to her companion. <speech ref="mayStainton">I suppose the new owner is
                    going to live here. It looks just as <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                        >dingy</scary_word> as ever; but you do not remember it, <character
                        ref="maryFenton">Mary</character>.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="maryFenton">I think I do,</speech> was the answer. <speech
                    ref="maryFenton">As I look the place grows familiar to me. I do recollect some
                    of the rooms, I am sure just like a <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                        >dream</scary_word>, as I remember <character ref="georgeStainton"
                        >Georgie</character>. What I would give to have a peep inside.</speech></p>
            <p>At this juncture the new owner emerged from amongst the bushes, and, opening the
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">gate</scary_word>, asked if the ladies would
                like to look over the place.</p>
            <p>The elder hesitated; whilst the younger <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1"
                    >whispered</scary_word>, <speech ref="maryStainton">Oh aunt, pray
                do!</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="mayStainton">Thank you,</speech> said Mrs. <character
                    ref="mayStainton">May</character> to the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >stranger</scary_word>, whom she <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0"
                    >believed</scary_word> to be a gardener; <speech ref="mayStainton">but perhaps
                        <character ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character> might
                    object.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">No; he wouldn't, I know,</speech> declared the new
                owner. <speech ref="edgarStainton">You can go through the <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="1">house</scary_word> if you wish. There is no one in it. Nobody
                    lives there except myself.</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="mayStainton">Taking charge, I suppose?</speech> suggested Mrs.
                    <character ref="mayStainton">May</character> blandly.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">Something of that sort,</speech> he answered.</p>
            <p><speech ref="maryFenton">I do not think he is a caretaker,</speech> said the girl,
                as she and her relative passed into the old <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >house</scary_word> together.</p>
            <p><speech ref="mayStainton">What do you suppose he is, then?</speech> asked her
                aunt.</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="maryFenton"><character ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character>
                    himself.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="mayStainton">Nonsense, <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                        >child</scary_word>!</speech> exclaimed Mrs. <character ref="mayStainton"
                    >May</character>, turning, nevertheless, to one of the <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="1">windows</scary_word>, and casting a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                    >curious</scary_word> glance towards the new owner, who was now, his hands
                thrust <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">deep</scary_word> in his pockets, walking
                idly up and <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0">down</scary_word> the drive.</p>
            <p>After they had been all over the place, from hall to garret, with a peep into this
                room and a glance into that, Mrs. <character ref="mayStainton">May</character> found
                the man who puzzled her leaning against one of the pillars of the porch, waiting,
                apparently, for their reappearance.</p>
            <p><speech ref="mayStainton">I am sure we are <scary_word pos="mod" scale="i"
                        >very</scary_word> much obliged to you,</speech> she began, with a
                hesitation in her manner.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">Pray do not mention it,</speech> he said.</p>
            <p><speech ref="mayStainton">This young lady has <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                        >sad</scary_word> associations connected with the <scary_word pos="noun"
                        scale="1">house</scary_word>,</speech>
                <character ref="mayStainton">May</character> proceeded, <scary_word pos="adv"
                    scale="0">still</scary_word> doubtfully feeling her way.</p>
            <p>He turned his <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">eyes</scary_word> towards the girl for
                a moment, and, though her veil was <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0"
                >down</scary_word>, saw she had been <scary_word pos="verb" scale="1"
                    >weeping</scary_word>.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">I surmised as much,</speech> he replied. <speech
                    ref="edgarStainton">She is <character ref="maryFenton">Miss Fenton</character>,
                    is she not?</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="mayStainton">Yes, certainly,</speech> was the answer; <speech
                    ref="mayStainton">and you are—</speech></p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton"><character ref="edgarStainton">Edgar
                        Stainton</character>,</speech> said the new owner, holding out his
                hand.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">I am all <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                        >alone</scary_word> here,</speech> he went on, after the first explanations
                were over. <speech ref="edgarStainton">But I can manage to give you a cup of tea.
                    Pray do come in, and let me feel I am not entirely <scary_word pos="adj"
                        scale="1">alone</scary_word> in England.</speech></p>
            <p>Only too well pleased, Mrs. <character ref="mayStainton">May</character> complied,
                and ten minutes later the three were sitting round a <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="0">fire</scary_word>, the blaze of which leapt and flickered upon the
                walls and over the ceiling, casting bright lights on the <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="1">dingy</scary_word> mirrors and the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                    >dark</scary_word> oak shelves.</p>
            <p><speech ref="maryFenton">It is all coming back to me now,</speech> said the girl
                softly, addressing her aunt. <speech ref="maryFenton">Many an hour <character
                        ref="georgeStainton">Georgie</character> and I have sat on that hearth
                    seeing pictures in the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >fire</scary_word>.</speech></p>
            <p>But she did not see something which was even then standing <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="2">close</scary_word> beside her, and which the new owner had witnessed
                approach with a feeling of <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">terror</scary_word> that
                precluded speech.</p>
            <p>It was the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">child</scary_word>! The <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="3">child</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2">searching</scary_word> about no longer for
                something it failed to find, but standing at the girl's side <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="2">still</scary_word> and <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2"
                    >motionless</scary_word>, with its <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2"
                    >eyes</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2">fixed</scary_word> upon her face, and its
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">poor</scary_word>, <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="2">wasted</scary_word> figure nestling amongst the folds of her
                dress.</p>
            <p>Thank Heaven she does not see it! he thought, and drew his breath, relieved.</p>
            <p>No; she did not see it—though its <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">wan</scary_word>
                cheek <scary_word pos="verb" scale="3">touched</scary_word> her shoulder, though its
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">thin</scary_word> hand rested on her arm, though
                through the long conversation which <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2"
                    >followed</scary_word> it never moved from her side, nor turned its <scary_word
                    pos="adj" scale="2">wistful</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">eyes</scary_word> from her face.</p>
            <p>When she went away—when she took her fresh young beauty out of the <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="2">house</scary_word> it seemed to gladden and light up—the
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">child</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2">followed</scary_word> her to the threshold; and
                then in an <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">instant</scary_word> it <scary_word
                    pos="verb" scale="3">vanished</scary_word>, and <character ref="edgarStainton"
                    >Mr. Stainton</character> watched for its flitting up the staircase all in
                vain.</p>
            <p>But later on in the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">evening</scary_word>, when he
                was sitting <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">alone</scary_word> beside the
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">fire</scary_word>, with his <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="1">eyes</scary_word> bent on the glowing coals, and perhaps
                seeing pictures there, as <character ref="maryFenton">Mary</character> said she and
                her brother had done in their <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">lonely</scary_word>
                childhood, he felt conscious, even without looking round, that the<character
                    ref="georgeStainton">boy</character>was there once again.</p>
            <p>And when he fell to thinking of the long, long years during which the <scary_word
                    pos="adj" scale="2">dead</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">child</scary_word> had kept faithful and
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">weary</scary_word> watch for his sister,
                    <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2">searching</scary_word> through the <scary_word
                    pos="adj" scale="2">empty</scary_word> rooms for one who never came, and then
                bethought him of the sister to whom her <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2"
                    >dead</scary_word> brother had become but the vaguest of memories, of the
                summers and winters during the course of which she had probably forgotten him
                altogether, he sighed <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0">deeply</scary_word>; and heard
                his sigh <scary_word pos="verb" scale="3">echoed</scary_word> behind him in the
                merest <scary_word pos="adj" scale="3">faintest</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">whisper</scary_word>.</p>
            <p>More, when he, thinking <scary_word pos="adv" scale="0">deeply</scary_word> about his
                newly found relative and trying to recall each feature in her face, each tone of her
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">voice</scary_word>, found it impossible to
                dissociate the girl grown to womanhood from the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2"
                    >child</scary_word> he had pictured to himself as <scary_word pos="verb"
                    scale="2">wandering</scary_word> about the old <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >house</scary_word> in company with her twin brother, their arms twined
                together, their thoughts one, their sorrows one, their <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="1">poor</scary_word> pleasures one—he felt a <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="3">touch</scary_word> on his hand, and knew the<character
                    ref="georgeStainton">boy</character>was beside him, looking with <scary_word
                    pos="adj" scale="3">wistful</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="3">eyes</scary_word> into the <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="3">firelight</scary_word>, too.</p>
            <p>But when he turned he saw that <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">sadness</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2">clouded</scary_word> those <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="2">eyes</scary_word> no longer. She was found; the <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="2">lost</scary_word> had come again to meet a living friend on the once
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">desolate</scary_word> hearth, and up and
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">down</scary_word> the wide, <scary_word
                    pos="adj" scale="2">desolate</scary_word> staircase those <scary_word pos="adj"
                    scale="2">weary</scary_word> little feet pattered no longer.</p>
            <p>The quest was over, the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">search</scary_word> ended;
                into the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">darksome</scary_word> corners of that
                    <scary_word pos="adj" scale="2">dreary</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">house</scary_word> the <scary_word pos="noun"
                    scale="2">child</scary_word>'s glance <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2"
                    >peered</scary_word> no longer.</p>
            <p>She was come! Through years he had kept faithful watch for her, but the waiting was
                ended now.</p>
            <p>That <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1">night</scary_word>
                <character ref="edgarStainton">Edgar Stainton</character> slept soundly; and yet
                when morning dawned he knew that once in the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2"
                    >darkness</scary_word> he wakened suddenly and was conscious of a small,
                childish hand smoothing his pillow and <scary_word pos="verb" scale="3"
                    >touching</scary_word> his brow.</p>
            <p>Sweet were the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">dreams</scary_word> which visited his
                rest subsequently; sweet as ought to be the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >dreams</scary_word> of a man who had said to his own soul—and meant to hold
                fast by words he had spoken:</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton">As I deal by that orphan girl, so may God deal with
                    me!</speech>
            </p>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
            <chapTitle>The Missing Will</chapTitle>
            <p>Ere long there were changes in the old <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >house</scary_word>. Once again Mrs. <character ref="mrsToplis"
                    >Toplis</character> reigned there, but this time with servants under her—with
                maids she could scold and lads she could harass.</p>
            <p>The larder was well plenished, the cellars sufficiently stocked; <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="0">windows</scary_word> formerly <scary_word pos="adv"
                    scale="0">closely</scary_word>
                <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">shuttered</scary_word> now stood open to admit the
                    <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">air</scary_word>; and on the drive <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="0">grass</scary_word> grew no longer—too many <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="0">footsteps</scary_word> passed that way for <scary_word
                    pos="noun" scale="1">weeds</scary_word> to flourish.</p>
            <p>It was Christmas-time. The joints in the butchers' shops were gay with ribbons; the
                grocers' <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">windows</scary_word> were tricked out to
                delight the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">eyes</scary_word> of the—children,
                young and old, who passed along. In Mr. <character ref="mayStainton"
                >May</character>'s <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0">house</scary_word> up the
                Clapham Road all was excitement, for the whole of the family—father, mother,
                grown-up sons and daughters—girls <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">still</scary_word>
                in short frocks and boys in round jackets—were going to spend Christmas Eve with
                their newly-found cousin, whom they had adopted as a relation with a unanimity as
                rare as charming.</p>
            <p>Cousin <character ref="maryFenton">Mary</character> also was going—Cousin <character
                    ref="maryFenton">Mary</character> had got a new dress for the occasion, and was
                having her hair done up in a specially effective manner by Cissie <character
                    ref="mayStainton">May</character>, when the toilette proceedings were
                interrupted by half a dozen young <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >voices</scary_word> announcing:</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="mayStainton">A gentleman in the parlour wants to see you, <character
                        ref="maryFenton">Mary</character>. Pa says you are to make haste and come
                        <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">down</scary_word> immediately.</speech>
            </p>
            <p>Obediently <character ref="maryFenton">Mary</character> made haste as bidden and
                descended to the parlour, to find there the <character ref="clerk">clerk</character>
                from Timpsons' who met <character ref="edgarStainton">Mr. Stainton</character> on
                his arrival in London.</p>
            <p>His business was simple, but important. Once again he was the bearer of a letter from
                Timpson and Co., this time announcing to <character ref="maryFenton">Miss
                    Fenton</character> that the will of Mr. <character ref="felixStainton">Felix
                    Stainton</character> had been found, and that under it she was entitled to the
                interest of ten thousand pounds, secured upon the houses in Stainton Street.</p>
            <p><speech ref="maryFenton">Oh! aunt, Oh! uncle, how rich we shall be,</speech> cried
                the girl, running off to tell her cousins; but the uncle and aunt looked <scary_word
                    pos="adj" scale="1">grave</scary_word>. They were wondering how this will might
                effect <character ref="edgarStainton">Edgar Stainton</character>.</p>
            <p>While they were <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">still</scary_word> talking it
                over—after Timpsons' young man had taken his departure, Mr. <character
                    ref="edgarStainton">Edgar Stainton</character> himself arrived.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">Oh, it's all right!</speech> he said, in answer to
                their questions. <speech ref="edgarStainton">I found the will in the room where
                        <character ref="felixStainton">Felix Stainton</character>
                    <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2">died</scary_word>. Walnut-Tree <scary_word
                        pos="noun" scale="1">House</scary_word> and all the freeholds were left to
                    the <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1">poor</scary_word> little chap who
                        <scary_word pos="verb" scale="2">died</scary_word>, chargeable with
                        <character ref="maryFenton">Mary</character>'s ten thousand pounds, five
                    hundred to Mrs. <character ref="mrsToplis">Toplis</character>, and a few other
                    legacies. Failing <character ref="georgeStainton">George</character>, the
                    property was to come to me. I have been to <character ref="mrQuinance"
                        >Quinance</character>'s successor, and found out the old man and <character
                        ref="alfredStainton">Alfred</character> had a grievous quarrel, and that in
                    consequence he determined to cut him out altogether. Where is <character
                        ref="maryFenton">Mary</character>? I want to wish her joy.</speech></p>
            <p><character ref="maryFenton">Mary</character> was in the little conservatory,
                    <scary_word pos="verb" scale="0">searching</scary_word> for a rose to put in her
                pretty brown hair. He went straight up to her, and said:</p>
            <p>
                <speech ref="edgarStainton"><character ref="maryFenton">Mary</character>, dear, you
                    have had one Christmas gift <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                        >tonight</scary_word>, and I want you to take another with it.</speech>
            </p>
            <p><speech ref="maryFenton">What is it, Cousin <character ref="edgarStainton"
                        >Edgar</character>?</speech> she asked; but when she looked in his face she
                must have guessed his meaning, for she drooped her head, and began pulling her sweet
                rose to pieces.</p>
            <p>He took the flower, and with it her fingers.</p>
            <p><speech ref="edgarStainton">Will you have me, dear?</speech> he asked. <speech
                    ref="edgarStainton">I am but a <scary_word pos="adj" scale="1"
                        >rough</scary_word> fellow, I know; but I am true, and I love you
                    dearly.</speech></p>
            <p>Somehow, she answered him as he wished, and all spent a <scary_word pos="mod"
                    scale="i">very</scary_word> happy <scary_word pos="noun" scale="0"
                    >evening</scary_word> in the old <scary_word pos="noun" scale="1"
                    >house</scary_word>.</p>
            <p>Once, when he was standing <scary_word pos="adj" scale="0">close</scary_word> beside
                her in the familiar room, hand clasped in hand, <character ref="edgarStainton">Edgar
                    Stainton</character> saw the <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2">child</scary_word>
                looking at them.</p>
            <p>There was no sorrow or yearning in his <scary_word pos="noun" scale="2"
                    >eyes</scary_word> as he gazed—only a great peace, a calm which seemed to fill
                and light them with an exquisite beauty.</p>
        </chapter>
    </body>
</story>