<?xml-model href="../data/Schemas/schema_update_3.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<story>
    <meta>
        <title>John Charrington's Wedding</title>
        <author>Edith Nesbitt</author>
    </meta>
    <body>
        <plot point="protag"/>
        <p>No one ever thought that <character ref="mayForster">May Forster</character> would marry
                <character ref="johnCharrington">John Charrington</character>; but he thought
            differently, and things which <character ref="johnCharrington">John
                Charrington</character> intended had a <scary_word scale="1" pos="adj"
                >queer</scary_word> way of coming to pass. He asked her to marry him before he went
            up to Oxford. She laughed and refused him. He asked her again next time he came home.
            Again she laughed, <scary_word scale="1" pos="verb">tossed</scary_word> her dainty
            blonde head, and again refused. A third time he asked her; she said it was becoming a
            confirmed <scary_word scale="1" pos="adj">bad</scary_word> habit, and laughed at him
            more than ever.</p>
        <p><character ref="johnCharrington">John</character> was not the only man who wanted to
            marry her: she was the belle of our village coterie, and we were all in love with her
            more or less; it was a sort of fashion, like heliotrope ties or Inverness capes.
            Therefore we were as much annoyed as surprised when <character ref="johnCharrington"
                >John Charrington</character> walked into our little local Club—we held it in a loft
            over the saddler's, I remember—and invited us all to his wedding.</p>
        <p><speech ref="amb">Your wedding?</speech></p>
        <p><speech ref="amb">You don't mean it?</speech></p>
        <p><speech ref="amb">Who's the happy fair? When's it to be?</speech></p>
        <p><character ref="johnCharrington">John Charrington</character> filled his pipe and lighted
            it before he replied. Then he said—</p>
        <p><speech ref="johnCharrington">I'm sorry to deprive you fellows of your only joke—but
                    <character ref="mayForster">Miss Forster</character> and I are to be married in
                September.</speech></p>
        <p><speech ref="amb">You don't mean it?</speech></p>
        <p><speech ref="amb">He's got the mitten again, and it's turned his head.</speech></p>
        <p><speech ref="geoffrey">No,</speech> I said, rising, <speech ref="geoffrey">I see it's
                true. Lend me a pistol some one—or a first-class fare to the other end of Nowhere.
                Charrington has bewitched the only pretty girl in our twenty-mile radius. Was it
                mesmerism, or a love-potion, Jack?</speech></p>
        <p><speech ref="johnCharrington">Neither, sir, but a gift you'll never have—perseverance—and
                the best luck a man ever had in this world.</speech></p>
        <p>There was something in his <scary_word scale="1" pos="noun">voice</scary_word> that
            silenced me, and all chaff of the other fellows failed to draw him further.</p>
        <p>The queer thing about it was that when we congratulated <character ref="mayForster">Miss
                Forster</character>, she blushed and smiled and dimpled, for all the world as though
            she were in love with him, and had been in love with him all the time. Upon my word, I
            think she had. Women are <scary_word scale="1" pos="adj">strange</scary_word>
            creatures.</p>
        <p>We were all asked to the wedding. In Brixham every one who was anybody knew everybody
            else who was any one. My sisters were, I truly believe, more interested in the trousseau
            than the bride herself, and I was to be best man. The coming marriage was much canvassed
            at afternoon tea-tables, and at our little Club over the saddler's, and the question was
            always asked: <speech ref="amb">Does she care for him?</speech></p>
        <plot point="intro"/>
        <p>I used to ask that question myself in the early days of their engagement, but after a
            certain <scary_word scale="1" pos="noun">evening</scary_word> in August I never asked it
            again. I was coming home from the Club through the churchyard. Our church is on a
            thyme-grown hill, and the turf about it is so thick and soft that one's <scary_word
                scale="1" pos="noun">footsteps</scary_word> are noiseless.</p>
        <p>I made no sound as I vaulted the low lichened wall, and threaded my way between the
            tombstones. It was at the same <scary_word scale="1" pos="noun">instant</scary_word>
            that I heard <character ref="johnCharrington">John Charrington's</character>
            <scary_word scale="1" pos="noun">voice</scary_word>, and saw Her. <character
                ref="mayForster">May</character> was sitting on a low flat <scary_word scale="2"
                pos="noun">gravestone</scary_word>, her face turned towards the full splendour of
            the western sun. Its expression ended, at once and for ever, any question of love for
            him; it was transfigured to a beauty I should not have believed possible, even to that
            beautiful little face.</p>
        <p><character ref="johnCharrington">John</character> lay at her feet, and it was his
                <scary_word scale="1" pos="noun">voice</scary_word> that broke the <scary_word
                scale="1" pos="noun">stillness</scary_word> of the golden August <scary_word
                scale="1" pos="noun">evening</scary_word>.</p>
        <plot point="history"/>
        <p><speech ref="johnCharrington">My dear, my dear, <scary_phrase>I believe I should come
                    back from the <scary_word scale="2" pos="noun">dead</scary_word></scary_phrase>
                if you wanted me!</speech></p>
        <p>I coughed at once to indicate my presence, and passed on into the <scary_word scale="2"
                pos="noun">shadow</scary_word> fully enlightened.</p>
        <p>The wedding was to be early in September. Two days before I had to run up to town on
            business. The train was late, of course, for we are on the South-Eastern, and as I stood
            grumbling with my watch in my hand, whom should I see but <character
                ref="johnCharrington">John Charrington</character> and <character ref="mayForster"
                >May Forster</character>. They were walking up and down the unfrequented end of the
            platform, arm in arm, looking into each other's <scary_word scale="1" pos="noun"
                >eyes</scary_word>, careless of the sympathetic interest of the porters.</p>
        <p>Of course I knew better than to hesitate a moment before burying myself in the
            booking-office, and it was not till the train drew up at the platform, that I
            obtrusively passed the pair with my Gladstone, and took the corner in a first-class
            smoking-carriage. I did this with as good an air of not seeing them as I could assume. I
            pride myself on my discretion, but if <character ref="johnCharrington">John</character>
            were travelling <scary_word scale="0" pos="adv">alone</scary_word> I wanted his company.
            I had it.</p>
        <p><speech ref="johnCharrington">Hullo, old man,</speech> came his cheery <scary_word
                scale="1" pos="noun">voice</scary_word> as he swung his bag into my carriage;
                <speech ref="johnCharrington">here's luck; I was expecting a <scary_word scale="1"
                    pos="adj">dull</scary_word> journey!</speech></p>
        <p><speech ref="geoffrey">Where are you off to?</speech> I asked, discretion still bidding
            me turn my <scary_word scale="1" pos="noun">eyes</scary_word> away, though I saw,
            without looking, that hers were red-rimmed.</p>
        <p><speech ref="johnCharrington">To old <character ref="branbridge"
                >Branbridge</character>'s,</speech> he answered, shutting the door and leaning out
            for a last word with his sweetheart.</p>
        <p><speech ref="mayForster">Oh, I wish you wouldn't go, <character ref="johnCharrington"
                    >John</character>,</speech> she was saying in a low, earnest <scary_word
                scale="1" pos="noun">voice</scary_word>. <speech ref="mayForster">I feel certain
                something will happen.</speech></p>
        <p><speech ref="johnCharrington">Do you think I should let anything happen to keep me, and
                the day after to-morrow our wedding-day?</speech></p>
        <p><speech ref="mayForster">Don't go,</speech> she answered, with a pleading intensity which
            would have sent my Gladstone on to the platform and me after it. But she wasn't speaking
            to me. <character ref="johnCharrington">John Charrington</character> was made
            differently; he rarely changed his opinions, never his resolutions.</p>
        <p>He only stroked the little ungloved hands that lay on the carriage door.</p>
        <p><speech ref="johnCharrington">I must, <character ref="mayForster">May</character>. The
                old boy's been <scary_word scale="0" pos="adv">awfully</scary_word> good to me, and
                now he's <scary_word scale="0" pos="noun">dying</scary_word> I must go and see him,
                but I shall come home in time for——</speech> the rest of the parting was <scary_word
                scale="1" pos="verb">lost</scary_word> in a <scary_word scale="1" pos="noun"
                >whisper</scary_word> and in the <scary_word scale="1" pos="adj"
                >rattling</scary_word> lurch of the starting train.</p>
        <p><speech ref="mayForster">You're sure to come?</speech> she spoke as the train moved.</p>
        <p><speech ref="johnCharrington">Nothing shall keep me,</speech> he answered; and we steamed
            out. After he had seen the last of the little figure on the platform he leaned back in
            his corner and kept silence for a minute.</p>
        <p>When he spoke it was to explain to me that his godfather, whose heir he was, lay
                <scary_word scale="0" pos="verb">dying</scary_word> at Peasmarsh Place, some fifty
            miles away, and had sent for <character ref="johnCharrington">John</character>, and
                <character ref="johnCharrington">John</character> had felt bound to go.</p>
        <p><speech ref="johnCharrington">I shall be surely back to-morrow,</speech> he said, <speech
                ref="johnCharrington">or, if not, the day after, in heaps of time. Thank Heaven, one
                hasn't to get up in the middle of the <scary_word scale="1" pos="noun"
                    >night</scary_word> to get married nowadays!</speech></p>
        <p><speech ref="geoffrey">And suppose <character ref="branbridge">Mr. Branbridge</character>
                <scary_word scale="0" pos="verb">dies</scary_word>?</speech></p>
        <p><speech ref="johnCharrington"><scary_phrase>Alive or <scary_word scale="3" pos="noun"
                        >dead</scary_word> I mean to be married on Thursday!</scary_phrase></speech>
            <character ref="johnCharrington">John</character> answered, lighting a cigar and
            unfolding the Times.</p>
        <p>At Peasmarsh station we said <speech ref="johnCharrington">good-bye,</speech> and he got
            out, and I saw him ride off; I went on to London, where I stayed the <scary_word
                scale="1" pos="noun">night</scary_word>.</p>
        <p>When I got home the next afternoon, a <scary_word scale="i" pos="mod">very</scary_word>
            wet one, by the way, my <character ref="fanny">sister</character> greeted me with—</p>
        <p><speech ref="fanny">Where's <character ref="johnCharrington">Mr.
                Charrington</character>?</speech></p>
        <p><speech ref="geoffrey">Goodness knows,</speech> I answered testily. Every man, since
            Cain, has resented that kind of question.</p>
        <p><speech ref="fanny">I thought you might have heard from him,</speech> she went on,
                <speech ref="fanny">as you're to give him away to-morrow.</speech></p>
        <p><speech ref="geoffrey">Isn't he back?</speech> I asked, for I had confidently expected to
            find him at home.</p>
        <p><speech ref="fanny">No, <character ref="geoffrey">Geoffrey</character>,</speech>—my
                <character ref="fanny">sister</character>Fanny always had a way of jumping to
            conclusions, especially such conclusions as were least favourable to her
                fellow-creatures—<speech ref="fanny">he has not returned, and, what is more, you may
                depend upon it he won't. You mark my words, there'll be no wedding
                to-morrow.</speech></p>
        <p>My sister Fanny has a power of annoying me which no other human being possesses.</p>
        <p><speech ref="geoffrey">You mark my words,</speech> I retorted with asperity, <speech
                ref="geoffrey">you had better give up making such a <scary_word scale="0" pos="adj"
                    >thundering</scary_word> idiot of yourself. There'll be more wedding to-morrow
                than ever you'll take the first part in.</speech> A <scary_word scale="1" pos="noun"
                >prophecy</scary_word> which, by the way, came true.</p>
        <p>But though I could snarl confidently to my sister, I did not feel so comfortable when,
            late that <scary_word scale="1" pos="noun">night</scary_word>, I, standing on the
            doorstep of <character ref="johnCharrington">John</character>'s <scary_word scale="0"
                pos="noun">house</scary_word>, heard that he had not returned. I went home
                <scary_word scale="2" pos="adv">gloomily</scary_word> through the <scary_word
                scale="1" pos="noun">rain</scary_word>. Next morning brought a brilliant blue
                <scary_word scale="1" pos="noun">sky</scary_word>, gold sun, and all such softness
            of air and beauty of <scary_word scale="1" pos="noun">cloud</scary_word> as go to make
            up a perfect day. I woke with a vague feeling of having gone to bed anxious, and of
            being rather averse to facing that anxiety in the light of full wakefulness.</p>
        <p>But with my shaving-water came a note from <character ref="johnCharrington"
                >John</character> which relieved my mind and sent me up to the Forsters' with a
            light heart.</p>
        <p><character ref="mayForster">May</character> was in the garden. I saw her blue gown
            through the hollyhocks as the lodge <scary_word scale="1" pos="noun">gates</scary_word>
            swung to behind me. So I did not go up to the <scary_word scale="0" pos="noun"
                >house</scary_word>, but turned aside down the turfed path.</p>
        <p><speech ref="mayForster">He's written to you too,</speech> she said, without preliminary
            greeting, when I reached her side.</p>
        <p><speech ref="geoffrey">Yes, I'm to meet him at the station at three, and come straight on
                to the church.</speech></p>
        <p>Her face looked <scary_word scale="1" pos="adj">pale</scary_word>, but there was a
            brightness in her <scary_word scale="1" pos="noun">eyes</scary_word>, and a tender
            quiver about the mouth that spoke of renewed happiness.</p>
        <p><speech ref="mayForster"><character ref="branbridge">Mr. Branbridge</character> begged
                him so to stay another <scary_word scale="1" pos="noun">night</scary_word> that he
                had not the heart to refuse,</speech> she went on. <speech ref="mayForster">He is so
                kind, but I wish he hadn't stayed.</speech></p>
        <p>I was at the station at half-past two. I felt rather annoyed with <character
                ref="johnCharrington">John</character>. It seemed a sort of slight to the beautiful
            girl who loved him, that he should come as it were out of breath, and with the dust of
            travel upon him, to take her hand, which some of us would have given the best years of
            our lives to take.</p>
        <p>But when the three o'clock train glided in, and glided out again having brought no
            passengers to our little station, I was more than annoyed. There was no other train for
            thirty-five minutes; I calculated that, with much hurry, we might just get to the church
            in time for the ceremony; but, oh, what a fool to miss that first train! What other man
            could have done it?</p>
        <p>That thirty-five minutes seemed a year, as I wandered round the station reading the
            advertisements and the time-tables, and the company's bye-laws, and getting more and
            more <scary_word scale="0" pos="adj">angry</scary_word> with <character
                ref="johnCharrington">John Charrington</character>. This confidence in his own power
            of getting everything he wanted the minute he wanted it was leading him too far. I
                <scary_word scale="0" pos="verb">hate</scary_word> waiting. Every one does, but I
            believe I <scary_word scale="0" pos="verb">hate</scary_word> it more than any one else.
            The three thirty-five was late, of course.</p>
        <p>I ground my pipe between my teeth and stamped with impatience as I watched the signals.
            Click. The signal went down. Five minutes later I flung myself into the carriage that I
            had brought for <character ref="johnCharrington">John</character>.</p>
        <p><speech ref="geoffrey">Drive to the church!</speech> I said, as some one shut the door.
                <speech ref="geoffrey"><character ref="johnCharrington">Mr. Charrington</character>
                hasn't come by this train.</speech></p>
        <p>Anxiety now replaced anger. What had become of the man? Could he have been taken suddenly
                <scary_word scale="2" pos="noun">ill</scary_word>? I had never known him have a
            day's <scary_word scale="2" pos="noun">illness</scary_word> in his life. And even so he
            might have telegraphed. Some <scary_word scale="2" pos="adj">awful</scary_word> accident
            must have happened to him. The thought that he had played her false never—no, not for a
            moment—entered my head. Yes, something <scary_word scale="3" pos="noun"
                >terrible</scary_word> had happened to him, and on me lay the task of telling his
            bride. I almost wished the carriage would upset and break my head so that some one else
            might tell her, not I, who—but that's nothing to do with his story.</p>
        <p>It was five minutes to four as we drew up at the churchyard <scary_word scale="1"
                pos="noun">gate</scary_word>. A double row of eager on-lookers lined the path from
            lychgate to porch. I sprang from the carriage and passed up between them. Our gardener
            had a good front place near the door. I stopped.</p>
        <plot point="haunting"/>
        <p><speech ref="geoffrey">Are they waiting still, <character ref="byles"
                >Byles</character>?</speech> I asked, simply to gain time, for of course I knew they
            were by the waiting crowd's attentive attitude.</p>
        <p><speech ref="byles">Waiting, sir? No, no, sir; why, it must be over by now.</speech></p>
        <p><speech ref="geoffrey">Over! Then <character ref="johnCharrington">Mr.
                    Charrington</character>'s come?</speech></p>
        <p><speech ref="byles">To the minute, sir; must have missed you somehow, and, I say,
                sir,</speech> lowering his <scary_word scale="1" pos="noun">voice</scary_word>,
                <speech ref="byles">I never see Mr. <character ref="johnCharrington"
                    >John</character> the least bit so afore, but my opinion is he's been drinking
                pretty free. His clothes was all dusty and his face like a sheet. I tell you I
                didn't like the looks of him at all, and the folks inside are saying all sorts of
                things. You'll see, something's gone very <scary_word scale="2" pos="adj"
                    >wrong</scary_word> with Mr. <character ref="johnCharrington">John</character>,
                and he's tried liquor. <scary_phrase>He looked like a <scary_word scale="2"
                        pos="noun">ghost</scary_word></scary_phrase>, and in he went with his
                    <scary_word scale="2" pos="noun">eyes</scary_word> straight before him, with
                never a look or a word for none of us; him that was always such a
                gentleman!</speech></p>
        <p>I had never heard <character ref="byles">Byles</character> make so long a speech. The
            crowd in the churchyard were talking in <scary_word scale="1" pos="noun"
                >whispers</scary_word> and getting ready rice and slippers to throw at the bride and
            bridegroom. The ringers were ready with their hands on the ropes to ring out the merry
            peal as the bride and bridegroom should come out.</p>
        <p>A murmur from the church announced them; out they came. <character ref="byles"
                >Byles</character> was right. <character ref="johnCharrington">John
                Charrington</character> did not look himself. There was dust on his coat, his hair
            was disarranged. He seemed to have been in some row, for there was a <scary_word
                scale="2" pos="adj">black</scary_word> mark above his eyebrow. <scary_phrase>He was
                    <scary_word scale="3" pos="adv">deathly</scary_word>
                <scary_word scale="2" pos="adj">pale</scary_word></scary_phrase>. But his pallor was
            not greater than that of the bride, who might have been carved in ivory—dress, veil,
            orange blossoms, face and all.</p>
        <p>As they passed out the ringers stooped—there were six of them—and then, on the ears
            expecting the gay wedding peal, came <scary_phrase>the <scary_word scale="2" pos="adj"
                    >slow</scary_word>
                <scary_word scale="2" pos="noun">tolling</scary_word> of the <scary_word scale="3"
                    pos="noun">passing bell</scary_word></scary_phrase>.</p>
        <p>A thrill of <scary_word scale="3" pos="noun">horror</scary_word> at so foolish a jest
            from the ringers passed through us all. But the ringers themselves dropped the ropes and
            fled like rabbits out into the sunlight. The bride <scary_word scale="3" pos="verb"
                >shuddered</scary_word>, and <scary_phrase><scary_word scale="2" pos="adj"
                    >grey</scary_word>
                <scary_word scale="3" pos="noun">shadows</scary_word></scary_phrase> came about her
            mouth, but the bridegroom led her on down the path where the people stood with the
            handfuls of rice; but the handfuls were never thrown, and the wedding-bells never rang.
            In vain the ringers were urged to remedy their mistake: they protested with many
                <scary_word scale="1" pos="adj">whispered</scary_word> expletives that they would
            see themselves further first.</p>
        <p><scary_phrase>In a <scary_word scale="2" pos="noun">hush</scary_word> like the
                    <scary_word scale="2" pos="noun">hush</scary_word> in the chamber of <scary_word
                    scale="3" pos="noun">death</scary_word> the bridal pair <scary_word scale="2"
                    pos="verb">passed</scary_word> into their carriage and its door <scary_word
                    scale="2" pos="verb">slammed</scary_word> behind them.</scary_phrase></p>
        <p>Then the tongues were loosed. A babel of anger, wonder, conjecture from the guests and
            the spectators.</p>
        <p><speech ref="oldForster">If I'd seen his condition, sir,</speech> said <character
                ref="oldForster">old Forster</character> to me as we drove off, <speech
                ref="oldForster">I would have stretched him on the floor of the church, sir, by
                Heaven I would, before I'd have let him marry my daughter!</speech></p>
        <p>Then he put his head out of the <scary_word scale="1" pos="noun">window</scary_word>.</p>
        <p><speech ref="oldForster">Drive like <scary_word scale="0" pos="noun"
                >hell</scary_word>,</speech> he <scary_word scale="2" pos="verb">cried</scary_word>
            to the coachman; <speech ref="oldForster">don't spare the horses.</speech></p>
        <p>He was obeyed. We passed the bride's carriage. I forebore to look at it, and <character
                ref="oldForster">old Forster</character> turned his head away and swore. We reached
            home before it.</p>
        <p>We stood in the hall doorway, in the blazing afternoon sun, and in about half a minute we
            heard wheels crunching the gravel. When the carriage stopped in front of the steps old
            Forster and I ran down.</p>
        <p><speech ref="oldForster"><scary_phrase>Great Heaven, the carriage is <scary_word
                        scale="3" pos="adj">empty</scary_word>! And yet<scary_word scale="3"
                        pos="mod">——</scary_word></scary_phrase></speech></p>
        <p>I had the door open in a minute, and this is what I saw—</p>
        <p>No sign of <character ref="johnCharrington">John Charrington</character>;
                <scary_phrase>and of <character ref="mayForster">May</character>, his wife, only a
                    <scary_word scale="3" pos="adj">huddled</scary_word>
                <scary_word scale="3" pos="noun">heap</scary_word> of <scary_word scale="3"
                    pos="adj">white</scary_word> satin lying half on the floor of the carriage and
                half on the seat.</scary_phrase></p>
        <p><speech ref="coachman">I drove straight here, sir,</speech> said the <character
                ref="coachman">coachman</character>, as the bride's father lifted her out; <speech ref="coachman">and I'll swear no one got out of the carriage.</speech></p>
        <p>We carried her into the <scary_word scale="2" pos="noun">house</scary_word> in her bridal
            dress and drew back her veil. I saw her face. Shall I ever forget it? <scary_word
                scale="3" pos="adj">White</scary_word>, <scary_word scale="3" pos="adj"
                >white</scary_word> and drawn with <scary_word scale="3" pos="noun"
                >agony</scary_word> and <scary_word scale="3" pos="noun">horror</scary_word>,
            bearing such a look of <scary_word scale="3" pos="noun">terror</scary_word> as I have
            never seen since except in <scary_word scale="3" pos="noun">dreams</scary_word>. And her
            hair, her radiant blonde hair, I tell you it was <scary_word scale="3" pos="adj"
                >white</scary_word> like snow.</p>
        <p>As we stood, her father and I, half <scary_word scale="3" pos="adj">mad</scary_word> with
            the <scary_word scale="3" pos="noun">horror</scary_word> and <scary_word scale="3"
                pos="noun">mystery</scary_word> of it, a boy came up the avenue—a telegraph boy.
            They brought the orange envelope to me. I tore it open.</p>
        <p>"<character ref="johnCharrington">Mr. Charrington</character> was thrown from the dogcart
            on his way to the station at half-past one. Killed on the spot!"</p>
        <p>And he was married to <character ref="mayForster">May Forster</character> in our parish
            church at half-past three, in presence of half the parish.</p>
        <p><speech ref="johnCharrington">I shall be married, dead or alive!</speech></p>
        <p>What had passed in that carriage on the homeward drive? No one knows—no one will ever
            know. Oh, <character ref="mayForster">May</character>! oh, my dear!</p>
        <p>Before a week was over they laid her beside her husband in our little churchyard on the
            thyme-covered hill—the churchyard where they had kept their love-trysts.</p>
        <plot point="resolve"/>
        <p>Thus was accomplished <character ref="johnCharrington">John Charrington</character>'s
            wedding.</p>
    </body>
</story>
